<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Ferenbrooke</title>
        <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com</link>
        <description>Tales of a Strange Town by Antony Frost</description>
		<item>
			<title>Returning to Writing</title>
			<link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/blog/returning-to-writing.html</link>
			<description>
               <![CDATA[It's been a long time since I've written creatively.

I've done a few blog posts about tech and politics on my other blog, but I haven't made stories in quite a while. I've really missed it. I wish I could have come back sooner, but things have been a tad crazy. I had a kid and then I almost died. It's all very dramatic, but that's not what I'm here to write about.

I'm genuinely excited by this little project. Serials and shorts written for pure fun, in my own weird little world. I have no idea if anyone will read it and I find myself not worrying much about it. It's a nice place to be as a hobbyist writer, really. I'm not sure if I'll do the whole submission grind thing later down the line, but for now having my own little corner of the internet where the only person I'm trying to please is me feels like the smart move.

I'll keep this first entry short and sweet, end it here.

Thanks for reading.

                    -Antony]]> 
</description>
		<pubDate>Tues, November 5 2024</pubDate>
	</item>
        <item>
            <title>The Landlord</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/short-stories/the-landlord.html</link>
            <description>
               <![CDATA[Lucy Hayward placed her mug down on her kitchen table, furrowed her
brow, and said, 'You're actually gonna do it?'

Chris O'Halloran, a good-natured Canadian from the flat across the
hallway, shrugged and said, 'Yeah, why not? He's paying.' He was sitting
on the other end of her sofa, sipping water, doing the neighbourly thing
and giving her the lay of the land.

Lucy shuddered. 'Albert's creepy as fuck,' she said.

She'd only moved in a few weeks previous and still held visceral
memories of his unsettling demeanour. It was an odd set-up, an acre of
land on the outskirts of Ferenbrooke with two houses upon it. One of the
buildings, post-war and generally bleak, became the block in which Lucy
and Chris, among others, lived. Albert occupied the older, grander,
red-brick Victorian house.

'He's a sculptor, an artist, they have to be a little off. It's the
law.'

Lucy smiled at this. 'How long does it take, modelling for a bust?'

'I said I'd give him two hours, and come back again if that wasn't
enough,' Chris said. He drained the last of his water and stood,
stretching. 'Thanks for the hospitality. Like I said, any questions you
give me a call.'

Lucy stood and walked him to the door. 'I will. And if you're not back
in two hours I'll send a search party.'

\#

Lucy sat alone in her top-floor flat and worried. Chris had been at
Albert's house for four hours at least. She occupied her usual perch,
the ledge under the window, opened a crack, with a hefty glass of
Tempranillo and a family pack of digestive biscuits. Her gaze flitted
back and forth between the front door and the rearmost window on the
ground floor of the landlord's house, clearly visible from her high
vantage point. She'd quickly figured out that said window belonged to
Albert's sculpting workshop; though the glass was frosted as one would
expect in a bathroom, he occasionally opened it an inch or two. A keen
eye could glimpse a table occupied by myriad tools and a stout wooden
chair flecked with grey clay. A keen eye with the aid of binoculars,
that is.

She couldn't shake the feeling that something was untoward. Was it
normal for landlords with creative hobbies to ask their tenants to
participate? To model for them? It made her uncomfortable in the
extreme.

Lucy pictured Albert's gnarled rat-paw hands forming and shaping and
reshaping Chris' head without tools, driving his yellow talon-like
fingernails into the eye sockets to form pupils. She shuddered, shook
her head involuntarily.

The wind was picking up. Faint howls of impatient air forced their way
through pine branches and past red brick walls, carrying earthy, herbal
chrysanthemum to Lucy's nose. She closed the window, conscious of the
chill in the air. The sky had darkened to the deep blue of her own
wine-stained lips, the glorious half-moon hovering above her landlord's
house, eagerly awaiting the arrival of its companion stars.

She spotted Chris, staggering up the pathway between Albert's front door
and their own. She squinted and rested her forehead on the glass, trying
to identify what was wrong with him. He looked pallid, grey almost, and
moved in a stiff manner. Lucy's jaw tightened; he seemed hurt, or unwell
in some way. She stood, left her wine glass and biscuits on the window
ledge and headed for the door.

Their paths met in the hallway, one floor below. Lucy's breath abandoned
her when she saw Chris. He was vacant-eyed. One hand supported him
against the wall while the other held a black scarf tight around his
neck.

'Hey, what's wrong?' she asked, trying to prevent any trace of the panic
she felt from entering her voice.

His eyes swivelled in his head and rested on her. He smiled sheepishly.
'Bed,' he said.

Lucy put an arm around him, took some of his weight. She helped him
climb the stairs and got him to his front door, where he fumbled with
his keys, dropping them. She retrieved them from the floor and unlocked
his door.

Chris stamped through his doorway and turned back to face her, stared
unblinking for a long moment, a stiff grin on his face. She met his
gaze, intended to speak, but couldn't summon any words to fill the
torturous silence.

With tears in her eyes, Lucy backed out of Chris' flat and shut the
door.

\#

The next morning, Lucy knocked on Chris' door.

No answer.

She walked the path to her landlord's door. The clay heads -- treated,
according to Albert, with a chemical process of his own design which
allowed them to survive outside -- lining the path were very impressive
up close; one could almost think the eyes were fixed on a person as they
passed, following each visitor for a moment before the grey faces
settled back into the repose of the never-living.

She cast a glance over her shoulder, regarded the serpentine route
she\'d just travelled. One of the watchful grey faces caught her eye. It
was different from the others, the clavicles of the bust faced forwards
as with the others but it turned at the neck to face the doorway of the
house where she now stood. It had a forlorn expression and its eyes
seemed fixed on her. She hadn\'t noticed it being that way when she\'d
passed it mere moments before. She kept her left hand in the deep pocket
of her long cardigan, which also contained an illicitly procured
miniature spray can of mace, and hammered Albert's door with her right.

Albert opened the door eventually. 'Good morning, Miss Hayward. What can
I do for you?' He spoke with a clarity and focus not typical of
men-of-leisure on crisp autumn mornings. He was a shortish, slight man,
pale and dark haired. He had an odd waxen quality to his face, could
have been anywhere from forty-five to sixty-five years old. He
absent-mindedly brushed fictional dust from a cashmere-clad shoulder and
quirked an eyebrow at Lucy.

'I was wondering, could I speak to you about Chris? Chris O'Halloran,
from the apartment next to mine? I'm worried about him.'

Alberts raised an eyebrow slightly. 'Please, come in.'

Lucy followed him into his home. They proceeded past two doors on the
right: the one to the study in which she'd signed her tenancy agreement,
and another which had a brass nameplate inscribed with 'Office &
Workshop'. Through that door would be the other side of the rearmost
window. After these, Albert stopped by a door on the left. He held it
open and waved Lucy through. She smiled faintly and nodded her thanks,
right hand on her mace within her voluminous right pocket.

It was a sitting room -- well, it'd more properly be referred to as a
drawing room in this sort of house, Lucy mused to herself -- decorated
in a lavish style reminiscent of the 1920s. The wood panelling on the
walls was painted a sombre greyish blue, three sofas formed a 'U' around
a broad oak coffee table in front of a fireplace, and the carpet was
thick and lush; so much so that Lucy felt a pang of guilt for wearing
her shoes inside.

Albert sat on the sofa opposite the fireplace, motioned for Lucy to sit
upon the one to the right. That would leave her back to the door. While
not keen on the idea, she didn't see much value in arguing, and so
followed his direction.

'So,' the landlord said, tapping his knees, 'How can I help?'

'I'm worried about Chris. He seemed so out of it when I saw him last
night, after leaving here. Like he was, I dunno, sick or something.'

Albert nodded. 'We had a couple of drinks after our session. You're
aware that I'm using him as a subject for my work?'

Lucy nodded. Smiled, insincerely. There had been no smell of alcohol on
Chris. And even if there had been, his demeanour wasn't that of a drunk.

Albert cleared his throat and continued, 'I'm sure he won't mind me
telling you this, he's also been using me to unload, so to speak. He has
a lot of anxiety. I won't go into specifics, but like many rudderless
young men he appreciates a...more seasoned ear. I like to think my true
purpose in life is not merely to recreate human heads through sculpture,
but to help mould the contents of them through wise guidance.'

'You're like Chris' counsellor?'

'Like a mentor, or a friend perhaps. I could be that for you too, you
know.'

She shook her head. 'I'm fine, thanks.'

'Your references from your last landlord suggest not,' he said, a hint
of toxic glee in his voice.

Lucy's eyes widened. She stuttered, wanting to say something but unable
to produce anything worth saying.

Albert smiled warmly, leant forwards in his chair, and steepled his
fingers while resting elbows on knees. 'Yes, that's right. You were
caught picking the lock on your housemate's door. You told her you
suspected her of some sordid crime or another, yes?'

Lucy swallowed. She said, 'Look, I was going through a bad time. My
thoughts...got away from me for a minute.'

'What thoughts were these, that got away from you?' Albert's cold eyes
bored into Lucy, rooted her in place.

'There had been a couple of home invasions. Witnesses said it was a
couple, a man and a woman. Killing whole families. Jenny and her
boyfriend fitted the descriptions. And you never know, you know?' she
paused, took a breath. She couldn't pull her eyes from his, couldn't
keep her mouth shut. She continued, 'I was obsessed, paranoid. I admit
it. But I'm fine now.'

'Paranoia isn't fine, and it doesn't go away on its own. I might be able
to help. It can be quite soothing, talking through your troubles while I
make you a head,' Albert said, breaking eye contact and nodding in the
direction of a woman's bust mounted above the fireplace.

Spell broken, Lucy glanced at the bust. Young, pretty, she thought. She
fancied she saw terror in those blank clay eyes.

Bile rose in her throat. 'Like you're helping Chris? He didn't seem to
be benefitting much last night.'

'Change is hard. Letting go of wild impulses, settling into a simpler
mindset of service and selflessness, it takes work. I'm sure he'd say
it's worth it, though. He's here now, actually. I think he might stay a
little while, considering the circumstances. Would you like to see him?'

As if on cue, the door behind Lucy's seat began to creak. She shot to
her feet and turned to face it, meeting Chris' vacant gaze as he
entered.

'Hi Lucy,' Chris said. He waved enthusiastically, a dumb grin on his
face, like a huge medicated toddler.

Lucy smiled at him then shot a look at Albert, who'd leant back into his
chosen sofa, arms splayed out across the back. She said, 'Well, since
we're all good here, I'll be off.'

'Of course, don't let us keep you,' said the Landlord, 'and do think on
my offer, won't you?'

'I will,' she said. She passed Chris, briefly giving him a one-armed
half-hug on the way and whispering, 'See you soon.' Within moments she
was back outside and halfway up the path. She paused a moment, turned
back and looked up at the landlord's house. Even in daylight it seemed
bathed in darkness. She knew she'd have to come back, figure out what
was going on.

\#

Every Saturday afternoon, around four PM, Albert left his house and went
out to dinner with his social club at Beaumont House, the two Michelin
star restaurant on the river. Lucy had seen him leave every week at the
same time and Chris had mentioned Albert's predilection for scallops and
sweet wines. A couple of casual walk-pasts of the restaurant had
confirmed her suspicions. Knowing this, Lucy gathered a few useful
objects (mace, gloves, jacket, the lockpicking kit she'd bought a few
years back) while glancing out the window from time to time.

He left right on schedule. Lucy considered it a safe bet that he'd not
return any time soon; it was usually close to midnight when he got home.
She hadn't seen Chris return, considered it likely that he was still in
Albert's house.

Her first stop was Chris' door. She knocked sharply, listened for any
movement. After five seconds of perfect silence, she crouched down and
spied through the keyhole. It afforded her no new information. So, was
Chris in his flat, asleep? Was he mindlessly staring at the wall? Was he
at Albert's? No way to tell.

Nothing for it. Now or never.

Did she want to go down this road again? Was this the same mental
bullshit that had chased her down the rabbit hole before? Chris could
just be processing trauma, Albert could just be a great talker who
actually cared. That was possible, right?

After a moment's deliberation, she exited her building. She walked out
through the garden gate to the road, not wanting any neighbour to spot
her walking between her home and Albert's. She walked around the
perimeter of the estate and advanced back up that same path she'd trod
the first time she saw her new home. She'd avoided that path as much as
possible since, didn't want to see those clay heads with their too-real
expressions and wanton disregard for good taste.

The gate shuddered open, seemingly hesitant to allow her passage. She
strode through hoping to look more determined than she felt. Gravel and
stone crunched and clicked as she made her way towards the house,
furtively glancing left and right.

Lucy stopped when she reached the part of the path where the heads
started.

They'd all been turned, all faced towards her. Fifty forlorn faces, grey
and motionless, gazing at her hopelessly.

Impossible ideas tugged at the neglected corners of her consciousness.
Had they turned of their own volition, knowing nobody was supposed to be
approaching? They do say that gargoyles and grotesques are supposed to
serve as guardians, no? Were these baked earth faces somehow aware of
her? Did they mean her harm?

Lunacy, of course. She knew that. Nonetheless she was tense as she made
her way past the heads, benefactors of Albert's proprietary
weather-proofing process.

She followed the wall around to a rear door, peeked in the window. The
kitchen. Quick look about, no company, no direct line of sight to any
windows. Perfect. She crouched down, pulled her roll of picks from the
inside pocket of her oversized leather jacket. She was a little rusty
but managed to pry open the door within a couple of minutes.

Inside, she closed the door behind her gently and immediately registered
a low, vibrating hum. She held her breath for a moment, ears pricked up
in search of the sound's source, and of any indication of Chris within
the landlord's house. After several long seconds, she was satisfied that
the hum was a product of some old machinery somewhere. It was an old
house, it could be some monstrous boiler far past its proper lifespan.
Perhaps something to do with Howard's sculpting. A furnace idling in the
workshop. She filled her lungs, nose wrinkling with the scent of far too
much air freshener.

Quick, light footsteps towards the front of the house. She passed the
doors which led to the living room and Albert's workshop -- she noted
the humming was louder there -- before stopping outside the study. If
there were answers to be found, that seemed like a good place to start.

She placed an ear against the door, counted to three. Nothing. At least,
nothing she could hear over whatever baroque machinery had been left
running. It was uncomfortably warm in the hallway; fine rivulets of
sweat formed on her brow. Her hand went to the door knob, eased it
counter-clockwise, and pushed it open. The slightest creak raised her
heart rate.

She slid into the study.

And was immediately grabbed and pushed sideways into a bookcase.

Chris had his hands around her throat, looking at nothing with vacant
eyes and an idiot grin.

Lucy's vision distorted almost immediately, the pressure on her carotid
artery sending sparks to her eyes and a thrumming whistle to her ears.
She moved her hands to his, tried to get her fingers between him and her
neck. No chance. He was not a large man, barely average in height, but
had the bear-like mitts of a seasoned labourer.

Mace.

Her hand went to her pocket, retrieved the small spray can. She mouthed,
'Sorry,' and unloaded the noxious pepper spray into her neighbours eyes.

He did not appear to notice. Didn't even blink.

Enough splashed back on Lucy to affect her, though.

Bile rose in her throat as liquid pain scraped and crawled through her
corneas, beat against the lenses of her eyes. The world grew dim and she
felt as though she were suddenly aware of the rotation of the Earth.

She dropped the mace can, clawed at Chris' face. Her right hand reached
to the bookshelf beside her, grabbed an ornament. She introduced it to
the side of Chris' head.

His grip slackened before falling away.

He crumpled to the ground, unmoving.

Lucy slid down the wall, gulping down mouthfuls of air that tasted like
blood and blinking away tears. She gingerly touched her neck, felt the
tenderness of her punished flesh.

When the room had righted itself and learned to stay still, Lucy rose
and cautiously stepped over to Chris' unmoving form.

Her eyes grew wide, her throat expelled a timid squeak.

She realised she was still holding the ornament used to dent Chris'
skull. She examined it momentarily. A little figurine in the style of a
grotesque, a bat-winged little distorted figure with animalistic
features and a weatherproof scowl.

Slowly her eyes drifted back to Chris.

To his dented, but not bleeding, head.

Where the skin had broken, it revealed greyish solid matter beneath.
Entirely unlike bone, it was more akin to the heads that lined Albert's
garden path.

She crouched, felt his neck for a pulse, felt nothing. Her cheeks grew
moist, but she stayed silent.

Chris' scarf had fallen loose when he hit the floor. Lucy's eyes were
drawn to a faint red line on his neck. She crouched down, removed the
scarf entirely. Her brow furrowed in confusion, jaw tightened with
barely suppressed horror. The red line was some sort of recent scar, no
doubt. She moved around her fallen friend, examined him from every
angle. The scar unquestionably circumnavigated his neck.

She stood, leant on the nearest wall and took several deep breaths.
Nothing made sense. Her eyes darted about the room, caught on the spine
of a particular book resting on Albert's desk. Something about it was
off, irregular. It had a sort of magnetism, or gravity. A compelling
force that drew her to it. Lucy stepped over Chris and approached the
desk, examined the book. The finish looked less professional than most
of the volumes in the library, possibly even hand-bound. The cover was a
sort of soft leather, no text on the spine to indicate what it
contained. Only a small spiral design. Her hand, almost of its own
accord, began to drift towards it.

The odd little book felt so strange in her hands, the coolness of the
thing penetrated through her gloves in barely a moment. She flicked
through a few pages. Obscure diagrams, anatomical studies of the human
head, what could be chemical formulae, every item of notation and every
word in a strange alphabet she'd never seen before. Utterly
undecipherable.

She grunted and snapped the book closed. She couldn't read it, but she'd
take it with her. She had to. It slid easily into one of her jacket's
voluminous side pockets.

She raised her left hand to her temple and rubbed in small circles. Her
heart threatened to burst out of her chest. Things had gone so damn
sideways, what was she supposed to do?

The only thing that seemed viable, sensible, was to continue searching,
to find out what Albert was doing to people. Chris couldn't be the only
one. But where next?

She paced in tiny circles, still rubbing her temple. Scattered thoughts
bounced off the walls of her skull and defied her attempts to rally
them. Her breath grew shallow and rapid. Sparks darted across her field
of vision. And she couldn't, not even for a moment, get the damn
thrumming out of her head. Mechanical noise picking at the frayed edges
of her composure. She hated it, Wanted to break whatever made it. Where?
*Where?!*

Her hands fell to her sides. She stopped, turned to face the door.

The workshop.

Once more she stepped over Chris. She left the study, closed the door
behind her, paced over to the workshop entrance. She had abandoned
caution by this point; anyone that hadn't heard her altercation with
Chris wasn't going to hear her stomping around and opening doors.

She let herself into the room. The hum became a cacophony and the
workshop stank of earth and turpentine. In the centre, two plastic
looking sofas faced each other with a small, cheap coffee table between.
The outside edges of the room were dominated by work surfaces containing
all manner of wicked looking tools; chisels and knives, hammers and
scalpels. Nothing out of the ordinary for a sculptor.

At the far end of the room was a small set of steps leading to a door, a
basement of some sort. The worst of the smell seemed to come from there.
That would likely be where the clay was kept and prepared.

The steps were slick, thin and treacherous. The door at the bottom was
locked, but only with a cheap padlock. Lucy quickly removed it with her
picks. More steps on the other side took her much deeper than she'd
expected the basement to go; the ceiling was high and there could easily
have been four feet of solid matter between that and the floor above.

The chamber was full of bulk bags of clay, shelves full of myriad vials
and flasks, stained books, obscure machinery. One huge and active
machine in particular noisily dominated the centre of the room, larger
even than the currently operating -- and blisteringly hot, even from the
stairway -- industrial oven at the far end. A huge brass and steel
frame, a lidded wooden box at the centre of it. Several glass flasks of
various fluids were suspended above a system of tubes, the whole thing a
circuit driven by what seemed to be steam pistons. The pressure no doubt
came from the oven, the heat from which probably produced the bubbling
in the largest of the three vials, filled with a milky liquid. The two
other flasks contained some thick brown substance, a consistency like
honey by the look of it. Down here a range of scents were on offer,
turpentine grappling with aniseed and mouldy earth for dominance.

Lucy advanced towards the lidded box at the centre of the contraption,
hand outreached for the handle at the front. Her fingers wrapped around
warm brass, lifted up the front of the box.

Inside, twitching, was Chris' head. Eyes and mouth sewn shut, rough
muslin around the base of the neck with tubes protruding out. The device
was pumping those strange liquids through the blood vessels of his
dismembered head, somehow keeping him alive, judging by the sweat and
the constantly shifting facial expressions.

Lucy screamed and backed away, kept stepping until her back met the
wall.

Then the door slammed.

She turned to face the stairs, her scream dying in her throat.

Albert stood at the entrance to the room, hammer and chisel in his left
and right hands respectively, with the lumbering form of Chris behind
him. Chris' head -- at least, the head currently residing atop his
shoulders -- was still dented, now shedding grey dust. One of his eyes
madly swivelled in the socket, the other stared blankly ahead. He still
wore that dumb grin.

'Your head's not right, young lady,' Albert said, 'But don't worry. I
can fix that.']]> 
</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, November 2 2024</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
