<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Ferenbrooke</title>
        <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com</link>
        <description>Tales of a Strange Town by Antony Frost</description>
        <item>
            <title>Nos Dat, Tad - Chapter 8</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/serials/nos-da-tad/chapter-8.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
I enter the spiral, Raincoat and the big fella following close. The first gold and silver double helix is embedded in the wall immediately to my left as I pass through the door at the bottom of the stairs. The floor tiles have been removed, revealing concrete. The brass filament is visible, curving round with the corridor, growing marginally more distant from the wall. Dim halogen striplights fail to erase the subterranean gloom.
<br/><br/>
I step forward slowly and examine the walls. Dull blue paint dressed with geometric diagrams and pictographic symbols that I can't possibly identify. There's something in the shape of them that's reminiscent of the writing in my father's journals.
<br/><br/>
Each double helix we pass is larger, more ornate, Simple threads of gold and silver become chains, then braids, then workings too fine for me to make out in the dim light. I glance back to examine the third for a second longer and catch a glimpse of a blood-spattered trainer around the bend. May. She's following us. I do my best to ensure that nothing shows on my face, no glimmer of hope among the waves of despair.
<br/><br/>
A hand on the shoulder forces me to stop. By my reckoning we've gone halfway around the circumference of the basement. To my left is a steel door secured with thick chains. To my right is a door emblazoned with a caduceus, the ancient Greek symbol for medicine consisting of two snakes around a winged rod, at the centre of a spiral with a series of eleven obscure sigils along its length. 
<br/><br/>
'In here,' Raincoat says.
<br/><br/>
I reach for the door handle, stumble with the sheer weight of the deja vu that hits me. My father knew the room behind the door well.
<br/><br/>
The smell hits me first. Liquorice, cinnamon, blood. It's overwhelming, takes me a moment to process. I adjust and look around the room. Less than a dozen candles provide light in a chamber twenty metres across. The spiral is barely visible on the ground, working its way towards some large device, something like an MRI machine. It's not clean and plastic like those in modern hospitals, it's brass and steel with a wooden bed engraved with those same geometric patterns and occult sigils I'd seen in my father's journals and the corridors outside. There's an upturned glass bottle full of a brownish liquid that's fed by tube into something like an old first world war blood transfusion kit, attached to the side of what would be the scanner in a conventional MRI. 
<br/><br/>
Something in me twists. I want to run. I don't know what that machine is but I know I don't want to be in it.
<br/><br/>
A man in black robes fiddles with dials on the machine with one hand, beckons me closer with the other. He wears an ornate headdress, a bulbous thing in blue with a livid red caduceus stitched into it and innumerable tendril-like strands falling down in every direction. 
<br/><br/>
As I approach him I notice that, deep within the shadows at the edges of this room ten more robed figures stand, statue-like.
<br/><br/>
'Where's Martin?' I say to the room.
<br/><br/>
The figure by the machine glances behind me. I turn and lock eyes with Raincoat.
<br/><br/>
'He's locked in a room upstairs,' he says, silky smooth and slow, like he's speaking to a dim child. 'You can see him later, if you cooperate.'
<br/><br/>
Over his shoulder, nauseatingly close to the big guy, I can see the tip of May's steel baton poke out from the hallway and give me a little wave.
<br/><br/>
I ignore this as much as I can and turn back to the machine and its operator.
<br/><br/>
The man removes his headdress and places it upon a steel work surface, next to a leather-bound book open to a page of diagrams much like those in my father's journal. An older white man with a thin beard. Furtive eyes and hollow cheeks. He smiles at me and says, 'I'm doctor Fry, you can call me Arthur. Do you understand the nature of the procedure today?'
<br/><br/>
I shake my head. 
<br/><br/>
'Good.' He pats the wooden table and beckons me closer. I tentatively approach, glance at the cloaked figures at the perimeter. They're stepping closer, closing me into a circle. Raincoat and the muscle step out and unlock the steel door opposite the entrance to this ritual chamber. 
<br/><br/>
Behind the door is a well-lit little room, bright enough for me to see the contents clearly. An onyx surface, an altar really, six feet long and about five feet off the ground. Upon the altar a decaying human body. 
<br/><br/>
My father's body.
<br/><br/>
The doctor clears his throat. 'I'll need you to lay on this table here. Time is a factor, my boy.'
<br/><br/>
I tear my eyes away from the mouldering remains of the father I never wanted to know and eye the door. I know I should try and make a break for it, try to get out. But my body is not solely my own anymore. I lay on the table as instructed. Fry secures my feet and hands with leather straps, then begins to fasten my head into a brace.
<br/><br/>
'How do I know Martin is still alive?' I ask.
<br/><br/>
'Well, quite simply we couldn't take the risk of killing him until we had you here. There was the distinct possibility that the process you've been undergoing would provide you with some of your father's more obscure skills. He'd be able to divine whether your partner was alive at a distance, which means that there's every chance you could too.' He fumbles with a strap he's trying to secure across my forehead then says, 'I have a question for you, actually. Your name. You were named for your father, and obviously think quite poorly of him, quite understandably, yet you never changed it. Why is that?'
<br/><br/>
I pause for a moment, order my thoughts. Then I say, 'It's my name. Mine. The fact that he has the same one is immaterial. I shouldn't have to change my identity because of his behaviour.'
<br/><br/>
Fry raises an eyebrow. 'Fascinating.' He finishes preparing my confinement and stands tall. 'Of course, you must now realise the power of names, due to your father's studies.' 
<br/><br/>
I do realise. 
<br/><br/>
'You've made our task quite a bit easier.' He turns to the bottle of brownish liquid and taps it twice. His eyes follow the route it takes into the pumps and bottles of the odd contraption next to that large chamber which resembles an MRI scanner less and less the more I see of it.
<br/><br/>
I now notice that from the other end of the medley of rubber and glass there extends a fine, clear tube which terminates in a hypodermic needle. I clench my fists. They're going to put that shit in me.
<br/><br/>
The doctor delicately grasps the needle and turns back to me. 'I can't promise this will be painless.'
<br/><br/>
'Is this what you did to your daughter?' I ask.
<br/><br/>
'Not precisely, no. The same substance was used, but the machinery had not yet been developed and I had a different aim. Regardless, Carla seems quite alright now. I count it as a success, she's so very useful to us. So obedient.'
<br/><br/>
The needle enters my forearm with vicious force. A static shock is closely followed by acidic maleficence entering my bloodstream, clawing its way towards my heart. He checks over my bindings one more time then nods towards the door. He dons his headdress and assumes a formal posture.
<br/><br/>
I strain to look around. The cloaked figures are closing in, forming a spiral with the machine, and me, at the centre. 
<br/><br/>
The doctor begins singing, mindless glossolalia in a high pitch. He operates the machine's controls with theatrical aplomb. The other cloaked figures join his meaningless garbling.
<br/><br/>
The machine whirs to life. The thick brown substance is pumped into me with increased vigour, burning and scratching as it enters. The scanner section begins to spin, and to glow a faint blue. The wooden table to which I'm fastened rises slightly and then approaches the scanner. I blink tears away, think of Martin and May, of Donald as well. 
<br/><br/>
I've doomed them all.
<br/><br/>
My head enters the scanner. Blue lights flit around me. The hum of the electrical coils harmonise with the cultist's chanting.
<br/><br/>
    My heart rate slows. Whatever they're putting in me doesn't hurt anymore. Calm washes over me, calm and distance. The light transforms, the sound transforms, the smells transform. Everything changes. I think I do, too.]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>End of Year Musings '24</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/blog/end-of-year-24.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
It's been a hell of a year in the F. household. I started 2024 unable to walk and uncertain that I ever would again due to the hit and run that I *never shut up about*. We had a one-year-old, my wife had not returned to work, and my job as a wax factory worker was looking untenable. I'd eventually get back on my feet with crutches in January, a walking stick in April, and unaided in June (except for the bad days). I returned to work in June, as well. Though I am currently off again since September due to mental health issues (the accident dramatically worsened my existing C-PTSD), I am certainly doing a lot better this year.
<br/><br/>
One of the big ticks in the plus column for EOY '24 over '23 is the fact that I'm writing again. I'd more or less stopped horror related activities after Jacob was born, unable to handle the combined stress of hard, physical shift work plus fatherhood plus my somewhat unhinged writing process. Returning has meant a lot to me. I think it took getting close enough to death to tickle the Grim Reaper's taint for me to realise just how important my silly little stories are to me, even if nobody is reading them. In fact, processing the accident by writing horror and weird fiction inspired by it is one of the first and most frequent things I thought about while I was in the hospital, aside from thoughts of my wife and son.
<br/><br/>
So yeah, I'm back in the game with this new website. It looks very retro and amateurish, which is exactly the look I'm going for (honest!). I want it to feel very human and raw, which is also how I want my stories to feel. I want it to nod vaguely in the direction of the web idealism of the late '90s and early 2000s rather than seamlessly blending in with the corporate web apps of 2024. A bit of a throwback. More Neocities than Squarespace (though I'm not using Neocities since I decided to spin up and manage an OpenBSD server myself. It's going for that same vibe, though).
<br/><br/>
But I digress.
<br/><br/>
What I want to do tonight is write a little about what I'm planning for Ferenbrooke in the coming year. I'll follow that up with a few paragraphs on what I'm happy about, and things I'm thankful for. It feels like a good and proper thing to do at the end of the year, and I'm sure my therapist would approve.
<br/><br/>
## The Horrors Shall Persist
<br/><br/>
Firstly, I'll be ending *Nos Da, Tad* with a new epilogue. This'll set up a couple of things which I'll be writing later in the year. That's all I'll say for now, but I think a couple of readers of the original version of *Nos Da, Tad* will be quite pleased if I'm remembering their comments correctly.
<br/><br/>
I've started loosely sketching out some ideas for the next serial, which I want to start posting in the Spring. It's going to focus on a down-and-out bartender coming across an alternative internet protocol and slowly uncovering a mystery around the creator of said protocol. It's inspired by Gopher and Gemini (not the Google thing, the [Gemini protocol](https://geminiprotocol.net/)) and the phenomenon of paranoia and conspiracy culture. I'm still workshopping a name, but I'm looking forward to getting right into the story. As a way of celebrating this story, I'll also be spinning up servers in Gopherspace and Geminispace and mirroring ferenbrooke.com there. I'm a big fan of these smaller, simpler protocols due to my old-man-esque feeling that the modern web is just too damn complex.
<br/><br/>
On the short story front, I've got a few recurring characters to introduce. One of them, a detective named Amy Russell, is also the protagonist of a novel I'm intermittently working on, so I'm quite keen to introduce her to the world outside my head. Another is Lucia Ivanova, the savvy mind behind the blog *Freaky Ferenbrooke* (mentioned in *The Rail House*). It's likely the blog will come up again before she makes an appearance, but I do want to get her on the page soonish. Ethan, from *Cat's Eyes*, might get another story. He sort of came out of nowhere. I wrote that story based on a recurring dream I've been having, so I was quite surprised to find myself getting such a strong sense of who Ethan is as a character quite quickly and I'm keen to see what happens if I throw some more strangeness his way.
<br/><br/>
My overall goal for Ferenbrooke is to have the stories largely work fine on their own, but also provide something extra for those who read more widely on the site. I'm trying to ensure that I don't accidentally write one giant mosaic novel where the stories don't individually work well without the larger context while also adding enough Easter eggs, references, and a sense of a larger narrative to make it rewarding to read the whole lot. It's a nontrivial target, but hopefully I'll hit it.
<br/><br/>
## Ending The Year With Gratitude
<br/><br/>
Dr. Andrews, this bit is for you.
<br/><br/>
I'm glad my son is getting a little older, a little smarter, and developing a strong personality. I'm glad my wife is enjoying being back at work and I am glad she gets to have her endometriosis surgery soon to improve her quality of life. I'm glad my family is safe and happy. I'm glad I can walk.
<br/><br/>
I'm glad I managed to get this site up. I'm glad that I've written every line of HTML, CSS, and XML myself rather than generating it (well, more or less. The prose is written in markdown then I convert it to HTML and wrap it in a template I made). That might change as this site grows, but the '90s style web dev experience is serving as a sort of mindfulness exercise right now. I'm glad I'm writing again, and glad that a few people are reading it.
<br/><br/>
I'm thankful for my wife and son, for their love and support, and for the continued understanding of my employer. I'm thankful, too, for the folks that have taken time out of their day to read the stuff I'm putting on this site. I'm thankful for my friends in the horror community and for all the cool indie authors and small presses that produced a tonne of new books for me to read now that I'm immersing myself in this little corner of the lit world again. 
<br/><br/>
I'm thankful for the people that heard the crash at 4:45am on 23/11/2023 and left their houses to see what happened. I'm thankful that they spotted my twisted, broken body in the ditch ten metres from my motorbike and called emergency services. I'm thankful for the air ambulance that pumped 5 units of blood into me to stave of haemorrhagic shock. I'm thankful for all the doctors, nursing staff, and other NHS workers that put me back together over the course of a month and five surgeries. I'm thankful for the synthetic bone graft in my left knee and for the 34 titanium implants in my left leg, pelvis, back, and right arm. I'm thankful for the fellow patients I met in hospital who made me feel a little more human while I was wired up to a bunch of machines and had a bunch of tubes going in and out of me. I'm *double* thankful for the silly amount of morphine I was on the whole time I was in the hospital.
<br/><br/>
And finally, I'm thankful for my scars. The ones you can see and the ones you can't. I might not like them, but they make me who I am, and that's worth something.
<br/><br/>
Thanks for reading.
<br/><br/>
    —Antony F.]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nos Da, Tad - Chapter 7</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/serials/nos-da-tad/chapter-7.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
The parking lot is desolate, empty. It's flanked on one side by the Fallow Park Surgery and the other by a prematurely wasted shell of a community centre, labelled as such by a graffiti-laden sign. A poorly maintained park with rusted swings and a patchwork slide lay in front of us as we drive in. Tall trees line every edge of the acre or so upon which the buildings and park sit. There's no direct line of sight to any domiciles and we're too far away from anything for sound to travel. You couldn't hope for more privacy without leaving the city.
<br/><br/>
May eases the car into a spot not too far from the surgery entrance. She looks at me with hard eyes, pronounced lines of tension in her forehead. 'You ready?' she asks.
<br/><br/>
I nod and turn to look at Donald in the back seat. His hands are folded into one another in his lap, sweat soaks his collar, but there's a serenity to his expression. He forces a quick smile and reaches to the footwell behind my seat. He pulls out the household implements we've armed ourselves with; a mallet for myself, a cricket bat for Donald. May is sticking with the collapsible steel baton she apparently carries with her everywhere.
<br/><br/>
Something stirs in me. Instinct. Whether native or invasive I can't be sure. 'I'm going in alone, I need to go in alone. If I'm not out in an hour then come say hi,' I say.
<br/><br/>
Nods from the other two, albeit hesitant. That'll have to do.
<br/><br/>
I take the mallet from Donald and exit the car. The other two step out and lean on the car, facing the surgery. I march towards the front door of the surgery, taking it on faith that my companions would do what I said. My heart assaults my sternum, my breath quickens.
<br/><br/>
The door opens as I approach. The man I think of as Raincoat is there, a jaunty smile on his lips and a twinkle in his eye. 'Hey, Owen. Good to see you. Please put your hammer on the ground and come in. I'll give you the tour.'
<br/><br/>
Something moves to my left. I barely catch it at the very edge of my perception. I glance over my shoulder and see a young woman holding a double-barrelled shotgun. There's nothing behind her eyes, she's the epitome of 'vacant stare'. It's unnerving. And how did she get there so fast? There's no cover for her to move in.
<br/><br/>
I suppose it's far from the strangest thing I've encountered recently. I turn my gaze back to Raincoat and slowly place my improvised weapon by my feet. He nods in response.
<br/><br/>
'Let's go,' he says. 'Carla, plug the extras.'
<br/><br/>
'Wait, no!' I shout. I turn and step towards the woman as she turns and brings the shotgun to her shoulder, aiming towards May.
<br/><br/>
It all happens so fast.
<br/><br/>
A belch of fire and thunder leaves a metal tube.
<br/><br/>
I see Donald throwing himself in front of May.
<br/><br/>
Scarlet erupts from his chest and he falls backwards, knocking my sister down.
<br/><br/>
I tackle the woman from behind, force her to the ground and position myself on top. I throw the firearm away, use my bodyweight to get her arms behind her back and hold them there.
<br/><br/>
I glance up to check that May's alive. She screams and cradles Donald's face, crying. 
<br/><br/>
Donald's face. There's nothing there, no movement. Only an echo of the serenity he wore moments ago in the car.
<br/><br/>
Hands grab me, two under each armpit. They pull me to a standing position. Two more guys, thuggish looking, football hooligan types.
<br/><br/>
'Come on now, Owen, we're on a schedule here. Time to stop dicking about,' Raincoat says. 
<br/><br/>
The woman Raincoat called Carla is back on her feet, looking for her gun. I hadn't thrown it that far; the thing was surprisingly heavy. May's nowhere to be seen, Donald's body is crumpled against the car, its silver body panels patched crimson with his blood. The apelike men on either side of me drag me through the doorway, through a clearly abandoned hallway to another door. Raincoat holds it open and his glamorous assistants push me through first. I can't find it in myself to resist.
<br/><br/>
    Behind me, Raincoat says, 'Keith, take Carla and find the sister. And clean up out there. We'll take Owen to see the doctor.']]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Rail House</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/short-stories/the-rail-house.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
'That's the last of them,' Mark said as he placed yet another cardboard box on the kitchen table. His face shone with sweat and joy, a broad smile parting his moustache from his beard.
<br/><br/>
Ivy paused her self-assigned task of filling the built-in kitchen cupboards with crockery and glassware and glanced at him, smiled. The last few weeks had been a blur. They'd put the offer in, squared it with the bank, gone through the bureaucratic purgatory of buying their first house with their first mortgage. So much had been done, and yet more remained. Not for the first time, she questioned their decision to move so close to Christmas. But she'd been the driving force behind the decision, and she would make it work, regardless of how much greyer it made her.
<br/><br/>
The eccentric little two-bed had been Little Chisden's rail station, left to lay fallow for a decade after its closure in the '70s and then revived as a home by an academic from Ferenbrooke University as the village was absorbed into the outskirts of the growing town. It sat upon the disused Victorian railway line that had once ushered steam engines from London to Lincoln. There was a picturesque terrace of railway worker cottages, now occupied by several families and a clutch of students, along the lane which branched off the village-turned-suburb's modest hight street. It was a huge change of environment from the melting pot that was Stone Street. Mark and Ivy had opted to trade a cluster of independent bars, artisan coffee shops, and oddball retailers for the old pubs and village green of Little Chisden once they hit their mid-30s and started thinking about growing their family.
<br/><br/>
'Thank fuck for the van,' Ivy said.
<br/><br/>
'One of several benefits of marrying a groundskeeper,' said Mark. He flexed his biceps theatrically. 'That and the incredible body.'
<br/><br/>
Ivy burst out laughing and collapsed against the kitchen counter. It wasn't that funny, but at this late stage of tiredness, inches from delirium, it was enough to break her focus entirely. 'I can't believe I have to work tonight,' she said, 'I'll be an utter mess by the end of it.'
<br/><br/>
'At least you've got Christmas off this year,' said Mark.
<br/><br/>
Ivy nodded. Last year had been rough. Her first Christmas without her father, who'd been lost to a heart attack in August, and she spent it in A&E in scrubs. Nursing was not a profession for the sentimental at the best of times, but that had been a real test of her resolve.
<br/><br/>
'Let's get the kitchen usable, then see if we can get the bedroom in vaguely the right shape before I set off,' she said.
<br/><br/>
Mark shook his head. 'You don't worry about that. I'll get our room sorted once you're gone. You've got more than enough on your plate.' He approached her and placed his hands on her upper arms, bent down to kiss her forehead. He stopped before his lips met her, though, and fixed his eyes on something through the kitchen window.
<br/><br/>
'Something wrong?' Ivy asked.
<br/><br/>
'Probably not. There's some old bloke looking at the house outside. Probably wondering who's bought it.'
<br/><br/>
Ivy turned to look. The man was certainly old, and certainly looking at their house. 'I'll go outside and see if he needs anything,' she said.
<br/><br/>
Mark nodded. 'I'll find the kettle.'
<br/><br/>
The kitchen was situated at the side of the house that faced the street, with the living room on the other side offering a view of the now-useless station platform. There were doors at both sides, one attached directly to the living room and the other at the end of a corridor flanked by the kitchen and the bathroom. Ivy negotiated that corridor slowly, carving a path between bags and boxes and bins—these full of tinsel and bows—that Mark had gracelessly deposited.
<br/><br/>
Once at the door, she pulled it open a little too fast and called out, 'Can I help you?'
<br/><br/>
The old man startled and said back, 'Oh, no. Sorry, you must think I'm rather strange. Nothing sinister is afoot, I assure you. I worked here, once upon a time, and live locally. I like to come back and look at the place once or twice this time of year. Sorry, I knew the last man that lived here, it didn't bother him. Old habits, and all that.'
<br/><br/>
Ivy softened her expression. The station had shut in the '70s and this man still came to visit. There was something sweet about that. Sweet and a little sad. People of that generation often made their profession the anchor of their identity. Losing this place must have been a blow. She made her way down the stone steps to the street and stuck out a hand. 'I'm Ivy,' she said. 'My husband's name is Mark. It's fine with us if you want to drop by and make sure we're not wrecking the place.'
<br/><br/>
The old man beamed. 'Henry Ericson,' he said, 'and thank you. I appreciate it. I'll continue on my walk, leave you to it. I'm sure you've got a lot to do.' With another smile and a feeble half-wave, Henry turned and ambled up the lane.
<br/><br/>
Ivy watched him for a moment before crossing the threshold and closing the door.
<br/><br/>
\#
<br/><br/>
It was close to 3am when Ivy guided her car into a space along the lane behind Mark's van. She was shattered, ruined, blood-speckled. The unfamiliar drive back, longer than she was used to, had necessitated the use of a SatNav and had tired her more than expected. She'd adapt, she was sure, but that first drive back had not been as trivial as the ten minute hop from the hospital to Stone Street had been.
<br/><br/>
The neighbourhood was so quiet. Even the wind dared only whisper as Ivy extracted herself from her cramped little Fiat and stood, arched her back briefly to hear the pops before she opened the car's rear door to retrieve her bag. The crunch of her feet on the dried leaves that littered the path leading to the house on the rails felt to her like an intrusion on the near-perfect stillness of the witching hour.
<br/><br/>
Pulling her keys from the small compartment of her backpack, she climbed the steps to the railway platform and looked left and right. The lights that had once dressed the station were long since gone, the only illumination that which seeped through the curtains in their living room window. Mark had always left a light on in the old flat when she was working late and she was glad to see that habit survive the move. The lack of light on the station platform irked her. It would be all too easy to take a step too far and fall onto the rails, particularly for the little feet they hoped would join them in the years to come. She decided to enquire with Mark about the feasibility of putting up a fence of some sort, and perhaps some outside lighting. 
<br/><br/>
In the dark, she cycled through her keys, trying to identify the right one for the front door. Or the back door. She wasn't entirely sure which side counted as the front or the back with the strange little converted property. She found what looked to be her target and released the breath she hadn't realised she'd been holding.
<br/><br/>
A clumsy attempt at putting the key in the lock sent her overburdened keyring tumbling to the ground. Ivy sighed and shook her head. It was a wonder any of the patients she saw towards the end of a shift made it with how clumsy her hands got when she was tired.
<br/><br/>
She squatted down and grabbed the keys, then stopped in that down position.
<br/><br/>
In the corner of her eye she saw something, some faint glow on the platform, not ten metres from the house.
<br/><br/>
She didn't dare move. Her heart was two-coffees quick all of a sudden and a new layer of sweat was making its home on her forehead.
<br/><br/>
It was silly, she *knew* it was silly. A little glow, probably a reflection from an overzealous Christmas light display a street or two away. 
<br/><br/>
But it spooked her.
<br/><br/>
Yes, that was the word. The combination of unexpected light with the strange, viscous silence of Little Chisden—a world away from the chronic busyness of Stone Street—had put a little scare into the air. Not unlike the grim silence of a room where a patient had just died in the hospital.
<br/><br/>
Ivy took a deep breath and forced her head to turn.
<br/><br/>
The glow was not a reflection. At least, not any sort of reflection that Ivy understood.
<br/><br/>
It was the vague shape of a person. A small person. A little girl in a big coat, walking along the very edge of the railway platform with her arms outstretched for balance. She wavered to the left and right while slowly edging forward.
<br/><br/>
Ivy stood and rubbed her eyes. Nothing there.
<br/><br/>
She shook her head. She was more tired than she'd realised. That must be it. Christ, she was lucky that her drive home had been so uneventful. 
<br/><br/>
On her second attempt, the key slid into the lock with no fuss and Ivy entered her new home. She kicked off her knock-off Crocs and shook out of her jacket, letting it fall to the carpet by the door. She thought about what she'd tell Mark in the morning while shuffling to the kitchen. Her body worked automatically while her mind wound down. Her hands retrieved a pasta bowl from the fridge, took off the tinfoil, and put it into the microwave. Her feet moved her to the counter where her eyes spotted a bottle of Merlot. Within a few minutes, she was sitting at the kitchen table without any real conscious idea of the process that had led to her slowly moving Spaghetti Bolognese from dish to mouth.
<br/><br/>
She looked around the kitchen while she chewed, relieved to see everything they'd brought in boxes had found a home. Even a few Christmas decorations were on show. A little snow globe on the high shelf over the table; a miniature tree garbed in miniature baubles and a tiny star on the counter by the kettle. 
<br/><br/>
Ivy wondered how long Mark had spent on the house while she'd been at work. Poor guy must be damn near as knackered as she is.
<br/><br/>
It was almost 3am when she finished her meal and washed it down with the wine. Ivy dragged herself to her feet and briefly considered just passing out on the sofa rather than braving the stares. She decided against it when thinking again of the strange image she'd seen outside. Being in close proximity to another person, especially Mark, felt like a good idea.
<br/><br/>
\#
<br/><br/>
The smell of bacon roused Ivy from dreamless sleep. She reached out for Mark and found his side of the bed empty. Grumbling, ragged with fatigue, she retrieved her phone from the bedside table. Almost 10am. Her dressing gown was hanging on the back of the bedroom door. 
<br/><br/>
By the time she'd made her way downstairs, teeth freshly brushed and hair left to wander, Mark had found the Bluetooth speaker and put on his favourite Spotify playlist of Christmas classics. He was frying bacon and sausages in one pan, eggs in another, while Dean Martin tried to control the weather.
<br/><br/>
'Mornin', gorgeous,' he said, smiling broadly and winking.
<br/><br/>
'Hey,' Ivy replied, 'how did you sleep?'
<br/><br/>
'Like a bloody corpse,' he said.
<br/><br/>
Ivy nodded. 'It's so quiet here.'
<br/><br/>
'Yeah, lovely.' Mark turned from the stove, pulled a chair from the kitchen table and gestured for Ivy to sit. She obeyed, pausing to plant a kiss on Mark's cheek. Mark placed a mug of steaming coffee in front of her. It was his favourite mug, a clumsily painted and misshapen thing given to him by his nephew. 'You have this,' he said, 'I just made it. I'll make myself another one.'
<br/><br/>
'You're too good to me,' Ivy said, sipping the dark liquid.
<br/><br/>
'Noted. I'll be sure to be a prick for the rest of the day to make up for it,' Mark replied. He filled the toaster with bread and turned the dial on the microwave, turning up the volume on the speaker to ensure that Judy Garland wouldn't be drowned out by the radioactive hum heating the beans.
<br/><br/>
A couple of golden oldies later, Mark was seated with Ivy, each of them in possession of a Full English and several beverages: OJ for vitamin C, tea for flavour, coffee for the will to live.
<br/><br/>
Ivy dug in, cutting up the bacon and sausages, poking bits of everything onto her fork and filling her mouth.
<br/><br/>
'How'd you find the first night in our new house, then?' Mark asked.
<br/><br/>
Ivy nodded, chewed fast and swallowed. 'Yeah, not bad. Bit weird coming back here instead of stone street. Drive was a lot longer.' She poked her beans, reticent to say the next sentence. 'Thought I saw a ghost.'
<br/><br/>
Mark froze. His fork was halfway between plate and mouth, his eyes were locked on Ivy.
<br/><br/>
Ivy chuckled. 'Sounds mad, doesn't it? Fatigue will do strange things to your perceptions, I guess.'
<br/><br/>
'Wasn't a little girl playing on the platform, was it?' Mark asked.
<br/><br/>
Hours passed with no gap in the back-and-forth. Ivy thanked her stars that neither of them had work that day. Between herself and Mark, they'd worked themselves into quite a state. Mark had seen it—her?—as well, before bed. Like Ivy, he'd assumed the stress and workload of moving had caused it. But both of them seeing the same thing? That merited a little more consideration.
<br/><br/>
After their long conversation, Ivy was indeed certain they'd seen the same thing. A young girl wearing a big coat. Mark's suggestions for naturalist causes ranged from implausible to legitimately less likely than ghosts.
<br/><br/>
'Hologram? Like the Abba shows?'
<br/><br/>
'Where would the projector be?'
<br/><br/>
'Silent stealth helicopter overhead?'
<br/><br/>
'Are silent stealth helicopters a thing?'
<br/><br/>
Mark went silent, focused on his phone. 'Doesn't seem like it,' he said eventually.
<br/><br/>
'Besides,' said Ivy, 'why would anyone go to the trouble of projecting the image of a little girl here?'
<br/><br/>
Ivy was about ready to crack open the Glenfiddich when a knock arrived at the door. She pulled her robe closed and approached the door, Mark following close behind.
<br/><br/>
Henry stood on the door step, a gift bag in hand. 'Terribly sorry, I don't mean to intrude,' he said. 'I brought you a little house warming gift. I hope that's not inappropriate.'
<br/><br/>
'Oh, no, that's very kind, thanks. I'd invite you in, but I was working late. I'm a nurse.'
<br/><br/>
'Of course, I understand.' He held out the gift bag. 'Here, have this. There's a card inside with my number. I'd be happy to give you a tour of the village, once you're both better settled in.'
<br/><br/>
'Thank you, that'd very kind,' said Mark. 
<br/><br/>
They exchanged polite goodbyes with their visitor and closed the door as he ambled down the steps. Ivy led Mark back to the kitchen table and put the gift bag on it, gesturing for Mark to do the honours. She thought of her father, of his propensity for gift giving at random times. It was pleasant to be reminded of him, though it was not without cost.
<br/><br/>
Mark first pulled an envelope from the bag which he opened to reveal a cute Christmas card with a cartoon reindeer on the front. He briefly read the card then set it standing on the table. Next he pulled out a small box, three inches square and made of wood. He looked at Ivy and raised an eyebrow.
<br/><br/>
Ivy shrugged. 'Might as well see what's inside,' she said.
<br/><br/>
Mark obediently opened the box. Inside was an old whistle engraved with the Little Chisden coat of arms. 'Oh, that's sweet,' Mark said.
<br/><br/>
Ivy nodded. 'Seems fitting.'
<br/><br/>
\#
<br/><br/>
The next morning, at Mark's request, Ivy called Henry and took him up on his offer of a village tour while Mark worked. She'd be off until Boxing Day, and he didn't like the idea of her sitting alone in a haunted house the whole time.
<br/><br/>
Henry knocked on the door barely an hour after Ivy called him. He was wrapped up warm in a thick cotton jumper with a comically long scarf underneath a wool overcoat. To Ivy's eye, he looked a little like Tom Baker's Doctor Who, give or take a few decades.
<br/><br/>
'I'm so glad you called,' he said once she had pulled on her thickest winter coat and joined him outside. 'It's always nice when new people are eager to learn the village's ways.'
<br/><br/>
'Well, I need to make sure this village isn't like a Wickerman situation,' Ivy said with a smile.
<br/><br/>
'Not at this time of year, no.'
<br/><br/>
Henry led Ivy on a calm and slow walk, starting at the point at which Station Road met the high street and progressing along the village, noting the historic pub and solitary newsagents on the corner and contrasting them with the more modern chain convenience store that occupied the middle spot of the road. Several other small outlets sparsely populated the street; two cafés, a hairdresser, a chip shop, a curry house, a charity shop. All along the route, Henry recited local history of note and just a sprinkling of gossip. At the end of the high street, an expanse of grass with a few trees and a pond marked the centre of the village. On the opposite side of the green, a small church neighboured another old pub. They grabbed coffees and pastries from the last shop on the high street, a charming bakery staffed by a woman with the broadest smile human anatomy would allow, and settled on a bench by the village sign on the green. The sign was weathered and imposing. It bore the same sigil as the whistle Henry had given Ivy and Mark.
<br/><br/>
'Thanks for the welcome gift, by the way,' Ivy said.
<br/><br/>
'No trouble,' Henry replied. He wore a faint smile, seemed peaceful. Ivy had seen the same look on her father's face, had missed it sorely.
<br/><br/>
Ivy looked at her coffee cup, swirled the contents. 'Listen, there's something I wanted to ask you.'
<br/><br/>
'Well, go right ahead.'
<br/><br/>
'Do you...have you every heard anything about the rail house being haunted?'
<br/><br/>
Henry sat up a little straighter. He inhaled deeply then said, 'I'd rather not discuss things like that, if it's all the same to you.'
<br/><br/>
'I just want to know if there were any stories like that when you worked there. When it was still a station. Did anything strange ever happen while you were there?'
<br/><br/>
'As I said, I don't wish to talk about fanciful old stories, or go drudging up ancient history.'
<br/><br/>
Ivy nodded. 'I understand.' And she did. She saw that kind of withdrawal quite often in the hospital, among people with fatty liver disease when asked how much they drank. 
<br/><br/>
\#
<br/><br/>
That night, once Mark was home, he and Ivy opted to stay up, together, bottles of lager in hand, with the curtains open in the living room. The TV was silent. Mark less so.
<br/><br/>
'If she turns up, who do we call?' He asked.
<br/><br/>
'Do you have the Ghostbusters' number?'
<br/><br/>
Mark shook his head.
<br/><br/>
Ivy rubbed his leg in a manner she hoped was consoling. She didn't look at his face. Her gaze was locked on the window and what lay beyond. She had told Mark about the conversation with Henry, about her belief that Henry was hiding something. What secrets could hide in a rail station? Illicit liaisons, criminals on the run, those things sounded plausible. But what could have happened to a little girl here?
<br/><br/>
The station platform seemed so different at night. Very little light made its way onto the slabs that constituted the platform and none onto the rails themselves. The lamp posts along the street stopped a dozen or so metres before the rail house, and the roof of the raised structure was taller than the lights themselves. In the December evening gloom, with what frail yellow light made it out of their home and into the night, Ivy could barely make out the faded line of paint that marked the point passengers should not stand beyond. The platform's slabs, composed of cracked concrete during the day, could have been a grey sea or an unusually flat storm cloud; in their near-invisibility their nature was only sure in memory.
<br/><br/>
Just as the sense of their silliness began to catch up with Ivy's paranormal enthusiasm and tipsy courage, just as the bedroom began singing its siren song, their patience was rewarded.
<br/><br/>
A faint glimmer at first. Like bluish gossamer floating on an idle air current. Then more. More size, more definite shape. The little legs poking out from the bottom of a massive coat, the outstretched arms, the head with sticking-out ears and a ponytail.
<br/><br/>
And then a little voice. Distant, quiet, hampered by both time and the wall between the source and the witnesses, but unmistakably there. High-pitched and with little in the way of rhythm, the sing-songy emanation reminded Ivy of a Christmas carol. Jingle Bells. 
<br/><br/>
They sat, enraptured, watching the curious display. Ivy felt time slow around her, felt space close in. Her internal map of everything decomposed in an instant. She'd been willing to write off the first encounter as a mental trick, but this new, complete vision was not so easily discarded. She managed to move her eyes briefly, to look at Mark. On his face she saw the perfect expression of what was going on in her own mind and she knew that they were really seeing something. Folie à deux can only take you so far.
<br/><br/>
Ivy stood and approached the window. Mark rose with her, the two of them moving in perfect synch. At the window, Mark unlatched the pane and opened it a crack, letting the strange little voice into their home with greater clarity.
<br/><br/>
The little girl—the little *ghost*—made her way from one side of the platform to the other, balanced right on the edge. She Teetered there a moment.
<br/><br/>
Then she fell onto the rails.
<br/><br/>
One brief yelp, and then nothing.
<br/><br/>
Ivy gasped.
<br/><br/>
Mark moved quick. He scrambled for the door, thumbed the latch and pulled it open, diving into the night.
<br/><br/>
Ivy regained her wits, pulled the window shut, and then followed Mark.
<br/><br/>
The air outside was bitter, unrelenting. Mark had made his way to the edge of the platform by the time Ivy was through the door. She called to him. 'Mark!'
<br/><br/>
He turned to face her, shrugged. 'Nothing's there.'
<br/><br/>
'Why did you run out like that?'
<br/><br/>
'Gut instinct, I guess.'
<br/><br/>
She reached him and looked down at the rails. Rusted but unbent, they seemed just like the relics they were. A glance at her phone. Almost 7pm. There seemed to be no pattern to when the ghost would appear; did it wait for someone to be there to watch?
<br/><br/>
After a few moments more of quiet thought, Ivy and Mark returned to the house. The windows in the living room were coated with frost on the inside.
<br/><br/>
\#
<br/><br/>
Ivy woke late. Mark was there, too. Ivy panicked and shook him awake, reminded him that he had work.
<br/><br/>
'No, I don't,' he mumbled from behind the pillow he was using to shield himself from light and wife. 'It's the 23rd today, love. No work now 'til January.'
<br/><br/>
'Oh,' Ivy replied, settling back into her side of the bed. It was, indeed, the 23rd. Time had quite gotten away from her. In earlier years, she'd always know when the 23rd hit. That was the day Dad came over. He'd stay until Boxing day, monopolising the TV and inflicting box sets of '70's crime shows on the household.
<br/><br/>
The morning, or what was left of it, moved slow. Mark made breakfast again and Ivy did the coffee. They chatted about normal things with a normal cadence and a normal amount of flat, tired jokes. But things were anything but normal. The tension was viscous, syrupy in the air. Once Ivy's belly was full, she broached the subject.
<br/><br/>
'So, what are we gonna do about the ghost situation?'
<br/><br/>
Mark shrugged. 'I really don't have a clue. I guess we need to figure out who it is. Check old newspapers, or something.'
<br/><br/>
Ivy nodded. She pulled out her phone and searched online for which libraries in Ferenbrooke kept the best local archives. After fifteen minutes and no success, she instead searched for Ferenbrooke hauntings. Hopefully there were local people who would know where to look, since it was by no means obvious from her search parameters.
<br/><br/>
There was a real wealth of Reddit posts and podcast episodes about strange happenings in the town, much more than Ivy expected. She'd considered Ferenbrooke a fairly dull place, as student towns go. Among the various incoherent screeds and 'just asking questions' conspiracy theories, she found a blog called Freaky Ferenbrooke which was well-constructed and contained thoroughly researched explorations of many local legends and unlikely stories. 
<br/><br/>
'Look at this,' Ivy said and sent the blog's URL to Mark. 
<br/><br/>
He pulled out his phone and read for ten minutes then said, 'Yeah, this looks promising. Maybe send this person an email, see if they know anything or can point you in the right direction.'
<br/><br/>
The Contact Me page listed the site owner as a Lucia Ivanova and supplied an email address. Ivy quickly penned a short, basic email and then handed it over to Mark to read.
<br/><br/>
`Dear Lucia,
<br/><br/>
My name's Ivy. I was wondering if you had ever heard about a haunting at the old rail station in Little Chisden? If so, could you possibly point me in the direction of some resources or further information?
<br/><br/>
Even if not, if you're aware of any stories of deaths at the station, particularly involving a young girl, I'd be grateful if you could share them with me. Incidentally, do you know which library holds local newspaper archives?
<br/><br/>
Thanks in advance,
<br/><br/>
Ivy`
<br/><br/>
'Looks good to me,' Mark said.
<br/><br/>
After pressing send, Ivy sighed and put her phone screen down on the table. Mark did the same and smiled at her. He was a good guy, kind and non-judgemental. Not for the first time, Ivy felt incredibly lucky to have him. There was nobody she'd rather spend Christmas with. She watched as he wordlessly stood and padded over to the kettle, switched it on and retrieved two mugs from the cupboard. Teabags went in, and then an almost embarrassing amount of sugar. And then Ivy's phone vibrated.
<br/><br/>
An email from Lucia.
<br/><br/>
Ivy rushed to the living room and retrieved her laptop from the sofa. She turned it on as she returned to the kitchen and sat it upon the table. Mark hovered while she waited for Gmail to load on the almost-antique netbook, fans whirring.
<br/><br/>
`Hi Ivy,
<br/><br/>
The story you're looking for is the disappearance of Millie Weir. 1973. Please find attached a scanned .pdf of the news article from the Ferenbrooke Inquirer, front page, 04th Jan. 1974. 
<br/><br/>
Numerous people have reported seeing the ghost of a little girl at the station over the years since. I'll attach a copy of my notes below. It's on my list of things to look into, simply haven't found anything substantial enough as of yet.
<br/><br/>
Let me know if I can be of any further help, and perhaps you could help me in return? If you've seen anything, or discovered any new information, I'd love to hear about it.
<br/><br/>
Kind regards,
<br/><br/>
Lucia Ivanova
<br/><br/>
P.S. The Ferenbrooke Community Library on Magdalene Street has the best archives outside the university's own, which they limit access to unless you're a student.`
<br/><br/>
Ivy exhaled slowly and opened up the first attached .pdf. Mark's breath on her neck informed her that he was reading over her shoulder. Good. That would save her having to explain everything. Hey eyes widened as she read; Millie Weir, nine years old, had been staying with her maternal grandmother. She had left the girl at the station where she was supposed to board the next train with her father (already on said train) who had been in Edinburgh on business and was returning home to Cambridge, picking up his daughter en route. Her mother had died two years previously, some sort of cancer. When the train stopped, Mr. Weir didn't see his daughter. He got off the train and asked the station master, Henry Ericson—*Henry*—if he'd seen her. He had, but not for some time due his duties requiring him to be in the office. The girl had not been seen since.
<br/><br/>
'Fuck,' Mark said, 'Henry has to know something.'
<br/><br/>
Ivy scrunched her brow. Mark was right. Too large a coincidence to ignore.
<br/><br/>
\#
<br/><br/>
It felt a little like a plot. Henry was so eager to come, so grateful for the invitation. It made Ivy feel like shit. What if they'd gotten it wrong? What if he wasn't hiding anything? It could just genuinely be awful for him to think about. The disappearance of a small girl on your watch is the sort of thing that could haunt a person.
<br/><br/>
But they had to resolve the situation somehow.
<br/><br/>
The living room was set well. All the detritus and inconsistencies produced by their move had been ably hidden by Mark in a fit of usefulness. The table had been reassembled and placed in front of the window, dressed with a festive cover, and left holding a slow cooker full of mulled wine and various savoury snacks. A bit much for a couple and a lonely old man, perhaps, but it felt appropriate for a Christmas Eve celebration. Perhaps less so for a ghost hunt and a potential interrogation, but neither Ivy nor Mark had any experience catering for those events. 
<br/><br/>
Henry arrived promptly at 5pm. Ivy greeted him at the door, smiling broadly. She led their guest into the living room, where Mark shook his hand with enthusiasm.
<br/><br/>
'Love what you've done with the place,' Henry said.
<br/><br/>
Mark chuckled. 'We haven't even really gotten started yet. Did you see the inside much with the previous owner?' He ladled mulled wine into a latte glass and handed it to their guest.
<br/><br/>
'Thanks. And yes, now and then. There was a twenty year gap between the rail station closing and Professor Langley buying the place. We struck up a bit of a friendship due to my habit of stopping by the place on my winter walks. Bit like our situation, I suppose.'
<br/><br/>
Ivy nodded, smiled. The previous owner, Professor Langley, had lived in this house for thirty years, grown old in it, died in it. She wondered what he'd seen, whether spectres joined him for Christmas Eve.
<br/><br/>
The three of them sat, Ivy and Mark on the sofa and Henry on a chair by the table, and chatted about past Christmases and family while a looping video of a crackling fireplace accompanied by festive piano music played on the TV. Once the mulled wine had settled into their stomachs and minds, Ivy decided to edge towards their purpose.
<br/><br/>
'What's it like, being back in this place?' She asked.
<br/><br/>
'Bittersweet, I'd say,' Henry replied. 'I had a lot of memories in this place. I was quite devastated when they shut the station down.'
<br/><br/>
Ivy glanced at Mark. He was staring at her. He was sweating. She nodded.
<br/><br/>
Mark cleared his throat. 'So, how long after that girl disappeared did they shut the place down?'
<br/><br/>
Henry froze. The room's temperature dropped. Slowly Henry's eyes slid from Ivy to Mark. 'I'm surprised you heard about that. It wasn't so long, six months or so.' His hands were shaking.
<br/><br/>
The weight of the tension in the air suffocated Ivy, made her feel twice as heavy. 'What happened, Henry?'
<br/><br/>
Henry's eyes narrowed. 'What do you mean by that?'
<br/><br/>
Mark rose. He walked to the table by the window, leant on it. He was facing away from Ivy and Henry, watching the platform.
<br/><br/>
'I mean,' Ivy said, 'I think you know why there's a ghost of a little girl haunting our house.'
<br/><br/>
A groan. 'Ridiculous. Ghosts. Come on, you can't be that daft.'
<br/><br/>
'We know what we saw,' Mark growled.
<br/><br/>
Henry rose, shaking his head. 'Bloody hell,' he said. He set his empty glass on the table and made for the door.
<br/><br/>
The key was in the lock. He turned it and threw the door open, marching out onto the platform. Ivy and Mark followed.
<br/><br/>
'Well then,' Henry said, 'where's your ghost? Is she going to appear in a window? Maybe step off a spectral train coming in from the coast? How does this work?' He waved his arms as he spoke, his voice rising with every word. His face grew red, contorted with emotions that Ivy couldn't recognise.
<br/><br/>
Mark pointed.
<br/><br/>
Ivy looked. Henry turned to look, too.
<br/><br/>
There, approaching the platform edge from the far end of the once-station, a bouncing little shape. Barely a whisper of light, four feet off the ground. 
<br/><br/>
It slowly grew more defined, became recognisable as a little girl in a big coat.
<br/><br/>
Henry gasped.
<br/><br/>
They stood, still in the freezing air, as the little spirit reached the edge and began its little nightly routine. Arms out for balance, one foot in front of the other, right on the edge. A clumsy rendition of Jingle Bells.
<br/><br/>
It lasted forever and a moment. She'd gone about eight metres, then lost her place in the song. Then lost her footing.
<br/><br/>
'No!' Henry shouted. He sprang towards the ghost as she let out a little yelp and disappeared over the edge of the platform.
<br/><br/>
Ivy and Mark followed him. They stood there, staring down at the rails.
<br/><br/>
For several painful moments there was only silence and the distant sound of a doorbell.
<br/><br/>
Henry drew in a deep rattling breath then said, 'I'd had a few drinks at lunch. There was only three trains that day, the one she was waiting for was the last. Her grandmother hadn't been well, asked me to keep an eye. I said I would, but I bloody well didn't. Fell asleep in my chair in the office. That yelp, that's what woke me.' Tears slid down his cheeks. 'I was terrified. Got it into my head they'd think I killed her. There'd been some murders in town and everyone was sure the wrong guy had gone down for them, stitched up to protect someone wealthy. Made me paranoid. So, I took her. I hid her away in...in the bloody shed.' He sobbed, held his face in his hands. 'Later, I moved her. Put her in my car, drove to the clay lake and buried her. There was construction going on, that Farrow Park mess. Plenty of holes, I just made one a little deeper.'
<br/><br/>
Henry fell to his knees, wailed. 'I'm sorry!'
<br/><br/>
Mark had his phone in his hand. Ivy's eyes widened. He'd recorded that confession. Mark nodded his head towards the house. Ivy nodded and went inside. She shut the door and leant against it, breathing heavily. With shaking hands she pulled her phone from the pocket of her hoodie and dialled for the police.
<br/><br/>
\#
<br/><br/>
They made it home by 11am, after a long night of being questioned by an Irish police detective who listened carefully and stroked his moustache as Ivy and Mark spoke. Henry had gone into custody without fuss and confessed again, rendering the recording on Mark's phone unneeded. Mark immediately set about preparing Christmas dinner. He propped up his phone against some cook books and video called his parents, encouraged Ivy to come into shot and wish them Merry Christmas. She obliged, but it felt hollow.
<br/><br/>
She slipped out of the kitchen when Mark began recounting their adventure and listened from the living room as Mark's father speculated wildly about which building the little girl would have been buried under. 'It'll be that block of flats by the crappy playground. Total eyesore. Clearly cursed.'
<br/><br/>
Once dinner was ready, the call ended and Mark joined her in the living room. They put on Home Alone and ate quietly. Ivy was entirely unwilling to risk a conversation that might turn to recent events.
<br/><br/>
The evening was a little more jovial. They sank a few beers, ate a lot of chocolate, and opened the presents they'd gotten one another. Ivy got Mark a Santoku knife and a pair of Doc Martens, in return she received a number of punk rock vinyls and a make-your-own scented candle kit.
<br/><br/>
They both kept looking out the window. Mark offered to close the curtains, but Ivy said no.
<br/><br/>
They were both waiting for it, and were braced and ready when it came.
<br/><br/>
The little girl singing Jingle Bells in the big coat.
<br/><br/>
The balancing act.
<br/><br/>
The slip.
<br/><br/>
        But this time, she found her footing. This time, she stepped back from the edge as the vague outline of something long and boxy drew up to the platform. This time, the vague impression of a door slid open and she stepped onto a ghostly carriage, to the waiting arms of a loving father. This time, she caught her train home for Christmas.]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nos Da, Tad - Chapter 6</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/serials/nos-da-tad/chapter-6.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
'I see,' Donald says. He's sitting at his kitchen table with May and myself, arms folded and leaning back in his chair. It's an odd look on him, but one he's maintained the whole way through my account of the events at the hotel room. I relayed everything I'd been through for which I have no explanation as well, in case the extra context is of any use. At no stage did he seem particularly shocked. Whether this is due to inherent unflappability or prior knowledge I can't be sure. 'I was not aware of the depth of his... proclivities. I'm sorry, Owen, so sorry. Have you called the police?'
<br/><br/>
'Yeah,' I respond, 'they said he's probably wandered off. Said to call 'em again in a week if he hasn't turned up.'
<br/><br/>
Donald nods. 'That sounds about right. They'll have received their orders, I suspect.'
<br/><br/>
My fists clench under the table. 'Their orders?'
<br/><br/>
'Oh, yes. I think I have an inkling of who took poor Martin, and they have quite a bit of influence in this town. No doubt the police are on their payroll to some extent. I imagine all towns have groups like it.'
<br/><br/>
'So, do you know where they are?' May asks.
<br/><br/>
'I think I do, yes.' He rises from his chair, motions for us to remain seated when we begin to follow his lead. He exits via a door that leads directly to his back garden and marches towards the shed.
<br/><br/>
I glance at May, who shrugs. 
<br/><br/>
We wait, silent and pensive. My outward calm, however, is a paradoxical symptom of the seething rage that vibrates my bones. My eyes dart from one object to another in Donald's kitchen, seeking any sign that he's involved with Raincoat and the rest of my father's clique. There's nothing, of course. It's an old man's kitchen, exceptional in its ordinariness. The only suspect item I see is a cookbook in French; only arseholes read French.
<br/><br/>
May clicks her tongue. When I glance at her she nods towards the window, through which I see Donald emerging from his shed with a beaten and tired leather portfolio tucked under one arm.
<br/><br/>
He re-enters the kitchen and reverently places the folder on the table. He's sweating, his jaw looks tight. 'You may remember me mentioning that I moved here to join an architectural firm in the late seventies. Among the first projects I worked on was a building that would become a GP surgery serving the northernmost section of Ferenbrooke, a newly built estate called Farrow Park,' he says. 'Your father moved here about twelve years later, after he screwed things up with your mother. He stayed with me a while, largely unable to hold down a job long enough to stand on his own two feet. As the eldest, I always felt somewhat responsible for my siblings, though I'd barely known your father. He was still a child when I left Aberystwyth.' He shakes his head then dumps himself down in his chair, rubs his forehead with the back of one thin hand.
<br/><br/>
May places a hand on Donald's shoulder. She regards him with a look of deep sympathy. She looks so much like our mother. I feel a pang of vicious jealousy and immediately hate myself for it. It's not her fault that I have to wear my father's face. 
<br/><br/>
Donald pats the hand on his shoulder and faintly smiles. He says, 'So, while I was suspicious of Owen turning up quite out of the blue I viewed it as an opportunity to get to know him. He, in turn, seemed to take an interest in my work on the Fallow Park Surgery project. The organisation that was funding it, a sort of club which claimed as members damn near everyone of any wealth and influence in the county, was previously unknown to me but had a reputation for throwing money at particular social causes so long as the money was used in very specific ways. In terms of the surgery project, they had quite a bit of input into the design. It's worth noting that basements in buildings such as this are uncommon around here; the ground isn't well suited to digging deep. Too close to sea level.' 
<br/><br/>
He opens the folder and pulls out an architectural plan. I bend over the table to examine it. The floor plan of the basement captures my attention. It's a round building, the stairs down to the basement are at the bottom edge of the plan, marked as south. A hallway circles the diameter, rooms seem to work their way inwards towards a large central chamber. There's a small triangular room off at the top, the only room that isn't within the circle. No equivalent room exists on the floor plan of either of the other floors.
<br/><br/>
Donald nods at me. 'When your father saw this, it sparked something in him, as it is in you now. I knew he was into some odd stuff, he collected old occult manuscripts and the like, used to shut himself away for days doing the oddest things. So, when he enquired as to the purpose of this building I quite naturally had my guard up a little. Eventually I softened and even had him do some of the grunt work, heading to the records office to pick up documents and the like. He attended a few of my meetings with the blokes in charge of funding the project, turns out he got along famously with them. Once the project, at least my part in it, was finished he took a job working for them and moved out quite quickly. He bought his house a year or so later and he barely had any time for me after that.'
<br/><br/>
He clears his throat and wipes sweat from his brow with a sleeve. 'Now, things get a little off kilter here. The Fallow Park Surgery only ended up operating for six years or so. It was shut down when the owner, and sole practising doctor there, a fellow by the name of Fry, was indicted for performing unapproved therapies on his own daughter. The poor girl needed quite some time in a mental institution to get back on her feet, or so I'm told. I'm unsure of what happened to the doctor but the building has been left empty since.' He taps the floor plan. 'This is where they'll be.'
<br/><br/>
'What makes you so sure?' I ask.
<br/><br/>
'Doctor Fry was, perhaps still is, a member of that club. I call them the Spiral Society, because of this nonsense,' he says, and traces his finger across the floor plan, going from the staircase to another point marked in red, then another, and so on, moving in a spiral pattern. 'Each of these points is marked by a double helix, of silver and gold, embedded into the brickwork. Brass filament below the floor links them in the spiral I'm indicating here. That's no coincidence, and there's no reason for it. No reason I'm aware of, anyway. The Spiral Society insisted on it. That's what got your father's attention, that and the onyx plinth in the room to the north.'
<br/><br/>
I nod. 'Thank you,' I say, 'you've been a big help. I'll go there and see what I can do. I'll call you as soon as I can. If I can.'
<br/><br/>
Donald stands and shakes his head. 'You're a damn fool if you think you're going without me, lad.'
<br/><br/>
    May says, 'Also, you can't drive. So I definitely need to come, if only to ferry you around.']]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nos Da, Tad - Chapter 5</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/serials/nos-da-tad/chapter-5.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
May sits across from me, concern painted across her round face. 'So this weirdo's been following you? He followed you here from Cambridge and he knows your name?'
<br/><br/>
'That's the long and short of it, yeah,' I say. I glance at Martin, feel a stab of guilt at his agitation.
<br/><br/>
I got off the bus in the town centre and called him rather than go to the library. I had been, simply put, a tad frantic. He had my sister in the car by then and they wasted no time getting from the train station to my location outside a grim little Italian café with a cracked window and hollow-eyed staff.
<br/><br/>
'You're going to call the police, yeah?' May asks. Commands, really. She's not known for her patience. Or her tolerance for disagreement. Or her gentle manners for that matter.
<br/><br/>
'And say what, exactly? Some fella in a brown coat, who I'm reasonably sure I've seen before, sat next to me on the bus? It hardly constitutes harassment, does it?'
<br/><br/>
A low growl, punctuated by a violent drop of the eyebrows, escapes my half-sister.
<br/><br/>
I appreciate her coming. Truly, I do. I'm not sure what good she can do though. The simple fact is that this situation has little to do with her. My father isn't her father, this isn't her mess to clean up. And while it's certainly proven to be an upsetting situation, there's no real indication that I'm in true danger. Creeped out, certainly.
<br/><br/>
Martin sits beside me on the hotel room bed and slings an arm around my shoulder. He says, 'do you think it's perhaps time we went home? We can come back and sort this shit another time. You need to rest, you need to prepare yourself properly before going any further with whatever this is.'
<br/><br/>
I wish, so profoundly, that I could simply agree with him. Unfortunately I know that escape isn't an option. I had burst the dam in my desire to taste the water behind it. There will be a flood, there's no getting around it. My best chance at survival is to go with the flow and hold my breath as long as I can.
<br/><br/>
'He's right,' May says. 'You're floundering, Owen. Weird blackouts and spontaneous nose bleeds is one thing, almost understandable given the circumstances, but a stalker is serious business. It's time to regroup.'
<br/><br/>
I sigh, shake my head. 'It's not that easy. I can't explain it but I need to see this thing through. It's now or never.'
<br/><br/>
My sister stands and walks towards the window. She eyes the car park, scans every corner, then draws the curtains closed and turns to face me. 'I don't like it, but I think I get it.'
<br/><br/>
I know she does. To some degree, anyway. She found her father shortly after Mum died. He's in prison for manslaughter. He nailed some kid with his car because he'd had more than a few before getting behind the wheel. As far as I know, May hasn't kept in touch with him, though she has developed something of a relationship with her half-siblings on that side. The whole deal messed her up good and proper. Hardened her.
<br/><br/>
Martin tuts and shakes his head. 'I suppose this means we're not heading back to Cambridge today,' he says to May.
<br/><br/>
'I think it's best that we support Owen through this. And we'll do it properly, responsibly,' May says to Martin before turning to me. 'You're not going anywhere or doing anything without one or both of us, got it?'
<br/><br/>
I nod while I stand. 'I'm going to the toilet. Either of you is welcome to join me, since you're so set on babysitting.'
<br/><br/>
Neither of them take me up on my offer. I make my way across the hotel room and seal myself inside the spacious bathroom. It's a nice space, welcoming neutral tones and a large mirror over the sink opposite an immaculate bath tub. Martin always insists on booking rooms with bathtubs, he can't stand showers and is clinically incapable of compromise when it comes to hygiene arrangements.
<br/><br/>
I sit down, take care of business, and linger for a few minutes, staring at my left hand. First the palm side, then the back. I wonder how similar my father's hands looked to my own. If you were to swap mine for his, my relatively clean fingers for the blood-stained digits of a predator, would I even notice? How would I ever know?
<br/><br/>
A knock on the door. Martin says, 'You alright in there, Fin?'
<br/><br/>
And so it begins.
<br/><br/>
'Fine,' I say, 'I'll just be a minute.'
<br/><br/>
I'm washing my hands and catastrophising about how overbearing my partner and sister are likely to be in the near future when I notice my reflection. It's different. Shorter. The eyes are wrong, the face is slightly off.
<br/><br/>
I examine the mirror, try to ascertain whether it's warped or twisted. Nothing seems out of place.
<br/><br/>
I step back, meet my own gaze. The quizzical expression on my reflection's face smooths, becomes a soft smile.
<br/><br/>
'Hello, son,' it says.
<br/><br/>
A feeling hits me, a dense compression. It's as though gravity is giving me special attention. Breath takes effort. I try to force air into my lungs, rapid shallow inhalations that provide nothing other than a destabilising spin at the peripherals.
<br/><br/>
My reflection—no, not mine. My birth father's reflection, occupying the place of my own, grins and raises its eyebrows. 'We're almost there. Almost ready,' it says.
<br/><br/>
'You're not real,' I say in a stage whisper.
<br/><br/>
'And you think you are?' it says. My father's reflection begins to raise its left hand, brings it to its shoulder and gives a little finger wiggling wave. 
<br/><br/>
My right follows. The involuntary role reversal disturbs the rapid thump of my heart, provokes an internal scream and a sudden expulsion of cold sweat.
<br/><br/>
The reflection belts out a single loud 'Ha!' and says, 'Now just stay put, enjoy the soundscapes.'
<br/><br/>
A crash from the other side of the door. I hear Martin's voice shout my name before a sickening thunk. A woman's scream. May. Metallic whistling, masculine grunting, the sound of breaking wood.
<br/><br/>
I want to turn away from the mirror and reach for the door but I can't. I'm stuck, locked in eye contact with a dead man. Is Martin okay? May? I'm here, alone—more or less—and the two people closest to me are out there with fuck knows what happening to them. I find myself yearning for any indication that those noises are simply an aspect of the hallucination, madness rather than malice visited on my family.
<br/><br/>
The chaotic rhythm of physical conflict plays out, too close for comfort and too far for agency. Things get very quiet for a moment, then I hear May shout, 'Fuck!' I hear several stomping footsteps and then hammering on the door. 'Owen, are you okay?!'
<br/><br/>
My father's reflection says, 'toodloo,' and I'm free. I divert my eyes from the glass, dive for the door and unlock it with shaking hands. Hands that are mine, for now.
<br/><br/>
My sister embraces me, tears streaking down her face. She's got a collapsible metal baton in one hand and her T-shirt is torn at the neck.
<br/><br/>
    'They came from nowhere, Owen, and they took Martin. I clocked one of 'em, he backed off and said Donald would know where to go. That's your uncle, right?']]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Cat's Eyes</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/short-stories/cats-eyes.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
With helmet in one hand and overladen saddle bags in the other, Ethan charged out into the bitter autumn evening from number 43 and let the door slam behind him. He glanced back at the building, once a large house for an expansive family and now three mediocre flats. One of them, until just that moment, had housed him and Erin. 
<br/><br/>
He wiped the wet from his eyes and stepped quickly to the road. His bike, an obedient if underpowered Royal Enfield Bullet 500, waited patiently. He unlocked the chain that bound it to the lamppost and fastened his bags, dropping the chain into a pouch on the largest sack-like bag which sat on the passenger seat. Within two minutes he'd fastened the clips and cords that secured his cargo. He stood back for a final visual check. Strange to think that he was leaving with so little. But that's how it was. 
<br/><br/>
Erin had been very clear. She was done. With him, with his lack of ambition, with his slovenly habits. And that meant he was done with the town. After dropping out of Uni, he'd only stayed in Ferenbrooke to be with her.
<br/><br/>
With a resigned shake of his head, Ethan swung his leg over his bike and sat in the saddle. He pulled his helmet on and fastened it while mentally repeating the riding advice his grandfather had shared with him a thousand times, until it had become lodged in his mind as a mantra.
<br/><br/>
<i>Don't ride angry.</i>
<br/><br/>
'Well, shit,' he muttered to himself.
<br/><br/>
<i>Assume everyone else is out to kill you.</i>
<br/><br/>
That, he could do.
<br/><br/>
<i>When there's no street lights at night, follow the cat's eyes.</i>
<br/><br/>
Ethan smiled at that. He'd been mystified by the little road reflectors when he was a young child, huddled in the back of Dad's Volvo during any one of their frequent long drives. He'd imagined an elaborate back-story linked to the name. That the cat's eyes really were just that; that cats laid submerged in the tarmac to guide drivers home. 
<br/><br/>
The sky had shifted to a moody navy blue while he'd been readying his departure. Lampposts began to wake while he inserted his key into the ignition and pulled on his gloves.
<br/><br/>
With a final deep inhale, Ethan put his hands on his bike's handlebars, thumbed the electric start, and kicked up the side stand. He knocked the burbling single-cylinder machine into gear and set off. To where? Who knows?
<br/><br/>
\#
<br/><br/>
Road passed quickly beneath him. His front tyre effortlessly weaved between potholes and detritus while Ethan kept his eyes up to monitor traffic and road signals. It was a quiet evening and there were few cars about. This part of town was largely residential and very well-lit, both by street lights and the windows of densely packed dwellings. The flat was near the hospital, south of the city centre. Supposedly Cheyford, the area they lived in, had once been a village that had been swallowed up by a metastatic Ferenbrooke. It was a common story, many of the outer areas of Ferenbrooke had their own names and stories. Like many such towns, Ferenbrooke was always growing, fuelled by old-money investment in new ideas which wanted to be near the University in order to harvest the emerging talent from its halls.
<br/><br/>
Socio-economic trends and half-forgotten history aside, the area had always been dull as far as Ethan was concerned. A mess of bland 80's houses, blocks of shit flats, decent old buildings renovated unto ruin and the occasional eighteenth-century pub hanging on for dear life. Generic little corner shops and precisely fuck all to do unless you were happy to walk 45 minutes into town.
<br/><br/>
They'd chosen to live there because Erin's work was at the hospital. She'd studied biomedical science and graduated into a clinical scientist training program. Unglamorous but crucial work in the blood lab.
<br/><br/>
Ethan chose his route carefully to avoid the city centre. He needed the north road out of Ferenbrooke, so that meant cutting through several residential areas and a couple of industrial estates. There was no ring road circling this town, unfortunately. It made the journey cumbersome. 
<br/><br/>
By the time he reached the north road, the night was full black and dotted with flickering stars. He switched to high-beams as he put Ferenbrooke behind him, pulled the throttle and then switched to a higher gear as he settled into a decent cruising speed. The cold air lashed his exposed neck and whistled through the air vents on his helmet, reminding him of riding pillion on his grandfather's bike during Christmas holiday visits.
<br/><br/>
Before long the road widened and the trees along either side of the road grew thicker. Ethan slowed slightly to account for lessened visibility with the thickness of the tree line and the winding shape of the road. Despite that precaution, he did not feel safe. Something deep in the oldest part of his brain was rustling uncomfortably, some atrophied instinct more at home in a burrowing mammal than a grown man. 
<br/><br/>
Up ahead of him, he saw the road do something unexpected.
<br/><br/>
The road he was on—the road he knew—meandered onwards for about ten miles with the occasional branch off towards a village or hamlet. So why was there a crossroad in front of him?
<br/><br/>
He slowed to a stop and took stock. No signs. No indication of where these new roads that looked as though they'd always been there would lead. 
<br/><br/>
Something caught his eye within the trees. A faint light, somewhere deep beyond the ragged rowans. Adventurous teenagers, perhaps.
<br/><br/>
He took a deep breath and set off again. Those roads and whoever was shining light off the beaten path would have to be someone else's problem. 
<br/><br/>
At least until Ethan found himself at a road closure half a mile down the road.
<br/><br/>
'Bollocks,' he said as he rolled to a stop in front of a large yellow sign which helpfully informed him that the north road would be closed until the next Thursday. 
<br/><br/>
He pulled his bike around and sped back down the road, heading south in geography as much as in spirit. The thought of returning to Ferenbrooke filled him with dread. He hated the place, always had. He couldn't go back. Not even for one night. 
<br/><br/>
And so, once he reached that perplexing crossroad, he turned left into uncharted territory with barely a second thought.
<br/><br/>
Within a mile a lay-by emerged. Ethan pulled in and knocked the Bullet into neutral then tugged off his gloves. He dug in his pocket for his phone, unlocked it and pulled up a map application. The app sputtered; no signal. Ethan sighed and replaced the phone in his pocket, readied himself, and set off again. There would be something soon, some sign or landmark he could use to find his way back onto familiar roads, he was sure of it.
<br/><br/>
The road continued on, writhing and rough. The trees either side became more twisted and gnarled as Ethan went on, lending the wind that worked its way through them a character somewhere between forlorn and seething. As that evening air sang its mournful song, Ethan found himself checking the treeline for disturbances, inconsistencies. He couldn't be sure, but he had the sensation of flashes of colour in his peripheral vision as he proceeded towards an uncertain destination.
<br/><br/>
Another three or so miles and Ethan became more sure that there was something in the woods, running parallel to him, something huge that effortlessly kept pace and cast off faint prismatic light as it moved. A vehicle, perhaps. One that managed to be silent somehow and had malfunctioning lights, just coincidentally going in the same direction. It was a comforting thought, that distant possibility, and Ethan clung to it.
<br/><br/>
Up ahead, the road forked. One road followed the tree line and the other curled off and was bordered by farmer's fields on both sides. Ethan took the latter, risking a quick glance back at the woods as they fell behind him.
<br/><br/>
Before long, lights appeared in the distance. They were the first he'd seen in some time and it occurred to him that the lack of other vehicles on his journey was a little strange.
<br/><br/>
It quickly became apparent that the lights he saw were not other vehicles. They were stationary, lights from some sort of building which was revealed to be a service station as Ethan drew closer. He breathed a sigh of relief. Fuel and a break were surely called for.
<br/><br/>
Ethan guided his bike off the road and into a waiting petrol pump station. He pulled off his helmet and gloves and plugged a pump into his tank. While his bike fed, he eyed the service station itself. It had a glass front, behind which there was a central seating area surrounded by a number of fast food outlets and a convenience store. A struggling fluorescent sign above the entrance declared the services to operate 24/7.
<br/><br/>
Once his tank was good and full, Ethan replaced the cap and pulled on his helmet. He parked his bike in one of the spaces by the services entrance and entered, removing his helmet once more. He made for the convenience store, where he paid for his petrol. The young guy who served him had a vaguely glazed look and didn't utter a word. 
<br/><br/>
Next to the store there was a chain coffee place. Ethan ordered a double espresso and acquired the WiFi password. Drink in hand, he sat at a table and pulled out his phone. He connected to the WiFi and opened his map app. The little spinning icon that indicated something was failing to happen mercilessly filled his screen. He sighed and put his phone on the table, leaned back in his chair and looked around. He was the only customer in there. Each of the tenant businesses had one or two staff members, which meant he was far from alone, but still it felt eerie. The buzz of chillers and pumps and uncared-for pipes were the only background sounds. No music, no chatter. 
<br/><br/>
The cashier from the convenience store had emerged from his perch, was stood in the doorway of his shop and eyeing Ethan. This made him a little uncomfortable. He cast his eyes around and saw that all the workers were looking at him. All had ceased whatever busywork had been inflicted upon them and stood, unblinking, unmoving. 
<br/><br/>
For the briefest of moments, Ethan was sure he saw some rainbow-like stream of light bounce from a barista to a burger cook.
<br/><br/>
As one, the workers began to move. They all walked towards Ethan's table, forming a loose circle.
<br/><br/>
Ethan's heart quickened. He didn't have a single clue what was happening, but he knew he wanted no part of it. He retrieved his phone from the table and stood, coffee forgotten. He marched for the entrance, cursing under his breathe when the convence store worker jogged to the door and locked it.
<br/><br/>
'Okay,' he shouted, 'just what the fuck is happening here?'
<br/><br/>
They were close now. The loose circle had tightened, losing all gaps and requiring some of the participants to look over the shoulders of their compatriots to get a good look at the lost biker.
<br/><br/>
Ethan locked eyes with the closest of them. Her eyes had pinhole pupils and the irises were rapidly cycling through every part of the visible light spectrum; one breath they were violet, then sunflower yellow, then a filthy orange.
<br/><br/>
Panicking, Ethan grabbed the only thing in reach, a chair, and swung wildly from left to right.
<br/><br/>
One of them was knocked down by the blow. His neighbour, a donut seller, caught the chair and tried to pull it away from Ethan.
<br/><br/>
Ethan responded by putting his weight into the chair, forcing his way forwards, pushing the worker back. A dozen or more hands grabbed at his jacket, most sliding off the slick leather, but a few finding purchase on straps and pockets.
<br/><br/>
The donut seller gritted his teeth as Ethan gained a little ground, then opened his mouth and released a fox-like wail. His face was barely a foot from Ethans, and Ethan winced at the sound, and then again at the blinding light emanating from the back of the donut seller's throat. 
<br/><br/>
Using every ounce of his blue-collar muscle, Ethan twisted the chair left and threw the donut seller to the floor. He sprinted through the gap in the crowd, elbowing aside a buffet server who launched herself at him.
<br/><br/>
Just inside the door, on either side, there were plastic palm trees about the height of a tall man. Ethan grabbed one and swung it 360 degrees before launching it at the large glass front of the building. It cracked and the plastic tree bounced off. Ethan swore again as the crowd caught up to him, all wailing now.
<br/><br/>
He threw a couple of punches and a clumsy kick, knocked a couple of them down. A particularly large barista grabbed his shoulders and pushed him back, into the cracked glass. 
<br/><br/>
Ethan crashed through, landed painfully on his side with chips of glass embedding themselves in his face and hands and the large barista on top of him. He shoved, elbowed, and kicked his assailant, dislodged him and scrambled towards his bike and mounted, shoved the key into the ignition, and kicked it into gear with more haste than he'd ever known.
<br/><br/>
He sped off without helmet or gloves. He looked into his mirrors and saw the crowd of service station workers gathering outside, shuddering as one, screaming. Light poured from their mouths and coalesced into a vague, shimmering shape. It was translucent, only visible at the edges. Something car-sized with a mess of legs. The workers collapsed as one when the shape left them, bounding after Ethan's bike.
<br/><br/>
Ethan pulled the throttle wide open and moved through the gears as quickly as he could. Short glances into his rear-view mirrors told him little. The shape, as realised as it was likely to be, was barely visible. It could have been gaining on him or not, there was no way to tell. 
<br/><br/>
Not until his left mirror disappeared, anyway.
<br/><br/>
A brief shriek of torn steel, a momentary flash of scarlet, and a twist of the handlebars to the left. Ethan struggled to right the Bullet's trajectory, managed to manhandle it away from the low stone wall lining the road. He wiped sweat from his eyes and brought his torso down to meet the petrol tank, praying to gods he'd never believed in for a little more speed.
<br/><br/>
Another fork in the road. He looked left, looked right. No signs. Looked left, then right. No idea where either would lead.
<br/><br/>
He spotted a faint reflective glimmer on the left road. Realised there was a line of them.
<br/><br/>
<i>Follow the cat's eyes.</i> 
<br/><br/>
The small reflectors were his beacons. If not a way home, they'd provide at least a course of travel other than <i>away from the thing behind.</i>
<br/><br/>
He glanced into his remaining rear-view mirror, saw it filled with cascading lights.
<br/><br/>
He leaned left, taking the turn faster than a rider of his limited skill had any right to. The bike's front wobbled dangerously as he straightened out, but he powered through and it regained stability. As he drew level with the first of the cat's eyes, a shriek of Biblical proportions erupted behind him. He powered on for three seconds, then turned his head and looked behind. The prismatic shape was stationary, quivering. It extended one of its uncountable limbs, recoiling as its own light was reflected upon it.
<br/><br/>
Ethan took a deep breath, exhaled slowly. He didn't dare slow until he saw the <i>Welcome to Ferenbrooke - Please Drive Carefully</i> sign on his left, accompanied by a camera and a 30 mile-per-hour limit. He glanced back again, saw the shape had not followed.
<br/><br/>
Obeying the limit, he cruised for a short while before finding himself on Camberton high street, one of the suburb areas a little way east of Stone Street. He turned off the high street and rolled to a stop behind a parked car, turned his bike off and ran his hands through his hair.
<br/><br/>
'Fuck,' he said.
<br/><br/>
'Bit brave,' said a voice behind him, 'riding without a helmet. They'll nick you for that, you know.'
<br/><br/>
Ethan turned and saw that the voice came from an elderly man with a dog and a gnarled cane.
<br/><br/>
'I lost it a little while back,' Ethan said weakly, 'Any idea if it's okay to park my bike here while I go home and get my spare?'
<br/><br/>
'Shouldn't be an issue,' the old man said. 'Lovely bike by the way. Enfield, is it? Where were you taking it?'
<br/><br/>
'I was leaving town. Got turned around.'
<br/><br/>
    The old man chuckled. 'Yes, that does happen. Sometimes, the town just isn't done with you.']]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nos Da, Tad - Chapter 4</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/serials/nos-da-tad/chapter-4.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
Martin puts his phone into his pocket as he enters our hotel room and smiles affectionately.
<br/><br/>
'Prynhawn da,' I say. I'm sitting at the hotel desk, laptop open.
<br/><br/>
'What's that?' Martin asks.
<br/><br/>
'Welsh for good afternoon,' I reply. 
<br/><br/>
'Since when do you know Welsh?'
<br/><br/>
I pause, unsure. 'Uh, must have picked up a word or two somewhere I guess.' It's a weak answer.
<br/><br/>
Martin shrugs it off. 'Okay. Well, anyway, I called your sister, she's coming here.'
<br/><br/>
'Martin, that should've been my decision.'
<br/><br/>
'You're right, but she can help and you never would've called her,' he says. His voice soft, his eyes moist. 'I was so worried last night. I'm still worried. That fucking...fit, or whatever it was, that was a bad sign.'
<br/><br/>
'It was a one-off. I'm fine,' I say, knowing I'm not.
<br/><br/>
'Look, you're going to need more support than I can give. And that's not because you're weak, it's because this mess is too big for the two of us.'
<br/><br/>
'She's got her own bullshit father to deal with,' I say, fully cognizant of the fact that he's done precisely the right thing. I'm not sure what's happening to me, but I do know it's outside my experience. May has lived a slightly more colourful life than I have; she may well have some insight that neither Martin nor I possess.
<br/><br/>
Martin sighs, places his hands on the back of the chair. We handed the box over to the police first thing in the morning. They won't be doing much -- the photos are from a long time ago, identification of the girls (now women, presumably) would be damn near impossible. And the perpetrator is dead. 
<br/><br/>
So, that's that. No closure for these victims, no retribution. And I'm supposed to carry on as if everything is normal.
<br/><br/>
'So when's May getting here?' I ask, 'We're meeting Donald for lunch, remember?' I'd messaged the old man in the morning, told him about what we'd found and arranged a lunch date to talk things through. I'm going to find out whether he knew of my father's proclivities.
<br/><br/>
'She should be here at about five, assuming the train doesn't take a wrong turn.'
<br/><br/>
I nod. It's been a while since I've seen my half-sister. Truth be told, I'm not sure I've seen her more than half a dozen times in the four years since mum's funeral. We were so very close for a few years there, much less so now. We message here and there, call once a month or so, but it's all pretty superficial. The mitochondrial ties that bind us feel so much less concrete without our dying mother here, pulling us together as surely as she falls apart herself. Cancer's a bastard.
<br/><br/>
We meander about our room, readying ourselves for what may prove to be the most awkward lunch appointment in human history. We agree that Martin will take the car to pick up May from the train station after lunch; I'll bus to the university library in the city centre and see if anyone can give me any information on the swirling, geometric script my birth father's journals are written in. I'd rather do that alone. I'm not sure why.
<br/><br/>
We arrive at the designated restaurant, a Dim Sum place with great Google reviews and stunning photos online, about ten minutes early. This proves fortunate, the nearest available parking is three streets away. From what I've seen thus far, Ferenbrooke is many things, driving friendly not among them.
<br/><br/>
The restaurant lives up to its digital reputation in appearance if nothing else. Classy red leather, oiled hardwood, brass fixtures as far as the eye can see, essentially a limitless distance due to the mirrored walls along either side of the long dining room.
<br/><br/>
Donald rises to meet us. He's at a circular booth table, the centre a raised plinth which no doubt spins. 
<br/><br/>
I shake his hand. Martin does the same. We sit, myself in the centre, Donald to my right and Martin my left. We allow Donald to order for us; the menu has some of the most laughable translations this side of social media. I'm certain it's a deliberate gimmick, much like the overplayed Chinese accent from our waiter, who switches to native Sheffield English when speaking to his colleagues.
<br/><br/>
Meritless small talk fills the table. I find out that Donald is a retired architect, that he never married and has no children of his own. He has five surviving siblings, younger than himself but older than my father. Catholic family, of course. Welsh father, Scottish mother. I hadn't known that I was part Scottish before.
<br/><br/>
When the food arrives, a veritable mountain of dishes in a cascade of colour, it's contained in the traditional bamboo steam pots common to Dim Sum restaurants. Gorgeously executed Chinese calligraphy graces the side of each. They bring to mind the obscure text in which my birth father's journals are written.
<br/><br/>
We pass around the dumplings, fill our plates with rice and shellfish, smile awkwardly at one another. I eat slowly, chew my food carefully. I am, in truth, not all that hungry. I didn't come here for a meal. I glance at Donald. It seems apparent that he didn't either. 
<br/><br/>
'So, Donald, you know we called the police this morning, right? They'll want to talk to you, to find out whether you knew about the photos.'
<br/><br/>
He pauses, places his chopsticks next to his plate, chews and swallows. His eyes close for a moment. A deep inhale through the nose, a slow exhale through the mouth. His eyes open and he adjusts the positioning of his chopsticks, lines them up, examines them more closely than I've ever looked at anything.
<br/><br/>
'I am fully aware, yes, the police have already contacted me,' he says, speaking slowly. 'I was not aware that my brother possessed photos like that, that he was doing things of that nature. I would have warned you, if I had known. I promise you.'
<br/><br/>
His face is angled down slightly, his eyebrows raised. His eyes are wide and sincere. I find myself inclined to believe him, though the rational part of my mind is reluctant to do so. 
<br/><br/>
'What do you know about his journals?' I ask. I reach into my messenger bag and retrieve the journal I'd brought from my birth father's house. I stack several of the bamboo containers atop one another to clear some space and place the journal down, angled for Donald to read, open at a random page. Donald pulls a pair of glasses from his inside pocket. He settles them on his nose and leans over the journal. His brow furrows as his eyes wander across the page, his gaze analysing the cryptic script with academic care.
<br/><br/>
'I've never seen this before,' he says, 'and I have no idea what it is. I couldn't even tell you what language it's in, I'm afraid.' He closes the journal, eyes the spiral design on the front for a long moment.
<br/><br/>
I sigh. I suspected he'd have no idea what it was, but nonetheless I had to check. Donald seems a simple enough fellow. I am, broadly speaking, a good judge of character. There is little doubt in my mind that this man, my uncle in the biological sense, is telling me the truth. He's as oblivious as I am. Perhaps more, given my recent tendency towards unwanted insight.
<br/><br/>
The rest of the meal passes calmly enough. It's quiet, almost sedate. Here and there Donald asks me little questions about unimportant facets of my life. Where I work, do I like it, what are my interests outside of work, the usual social garnish that people take in before they're ready to digest the meat of human interaction. Values, loyalties, responsibilities.
<br/><br/>
At the end, Donald pays. I notice that he leaves a good tip, shakes the waiter's hand. I like that. We part at the door of the restaurant. Martin makes for the car, Donald for the bus stop heading to his home in a village near town. I head for a bus aimed at the town centre and thus the university library. My messenger bag, with its cargo of cryptic texts, weighs heavy on my shoulder. I make it to the stop at the same time as the bus. I board, pay my fare, and sit towards the middle. I watch Georgian shop fronts fleet past, small crowds of teenagers block pathways, couples alone and with prams, solitary folk and pairs of friends. The town is alive, occupied, a moving moment in time. It's easy to think of it as nothing more than the setting for my father's story, the background for the life he's led since my mother nd he parted ways thirty years ago.
<br/><br/>
The world outside the bus passes ever faster. It produces a hypnagogic effect. The vibrations of the vehicle's engine sync up perfectly with the thrumming tinnitus in my ears.
<br/><br/>
That's new. 
<br/><br/>
My eyelids grow heavy. I force them up each time they fall, though it takes exponentially more effort with each drop. Once, twice, three, four times I teeter on the edge of sleep. I slip. For a moment I'm gone. The bus shudders in response to uneven road, I force my eyes open and I'm elsewhere.
<br/><br/>
It's a kitchen, cheaply outfitted with lino on the floors and chipboard work surfaces. A chest freezer sits beneath an unclean window, a rough and ready table against the wall.
<br/><br/>
A woman is screaming at me. I face her, my body doing what it will, my mind along for the ride.
<br/><br/>
'She's thirteen!' the woman screams at me. Her face...I know it. It's younger, thinner than I remember, and I haven't seen her in years, but I know that's my mother looking at me through tear-reddened eyes. A younger version of my mother without the scars on her face, but it's her.
<br/><br/>
I feel the burning in my stomach, the animalistic focus as a guttural roar forces its way up my throat. I raise my right hand to my left shoulder, feel the sick glee as my young mother flinches. I bask in that for a moment, wait for the moment she drops her hands from her face then deliver a savage back-hand that flings her into the door frame behind her. Her shriek just enrages me further. 
<br/><br/>
I take two steps towards her. She shrinks back, losing her spirit, her tears mingle with the blood dripping from the corner of her mouth.
<br/><br/>
'Look at you,' I say. 'You're a fat, screaming mess. Of course I went elsewhere. I have needs, you used-up bitch.' My voice is high, accented. 
<br/><br/>
My mother sobs, cradles her swollen belly with her arms. 'Can't you just leave me alone?' she pleads. 'Aren't we done?'
<br/><br/>
This breaks something in me. I grab a fistful of her top in my left hand and plunge my right into her face, again and again. I grunt out words between the blows.
<br/><br/>
'WE'RE'
<br/><br/>
*Punch.* Something cracks in her cheek.
<br/><br/>
'DONE'
<br/><br/>
*Punch.* Her left eye is swollen closed.
<br/><br/>
'WHEN'
<br/><br/>
*Punch.*  The split in her lip opens further, revealing cracked teeth and ravaged gums.
<br/><br/>
'I'
<br/><br/>
*Punch.* I open a fresh cut on her eyebrow. Warm blood coats my knuckles, gets into the abrasions I've received from pounding her face. It stings. This pisses me off.
<br/><br/>
'SAY'
<br/><br/>
*Punch.* Harder this time. She tries to duck her head down, I end up hitting her forehead. There's a sick cracking sound, a flare of pain in my palm. I let her go and stagger backwards, cradling my broken hand.
<br/><br/>
'You fucking cunt!' I shout. 
<br/><br/>
She slips down to the ground, weeping. Her face is purple, black, blue, blood-soaked. Bruised, battered, dented and swollen beyond recognition. She's still guarding her belly with her arms. She chose to defend her baby rather than herself.
<br/><br/>
Her baby.
<br/><br/>
Me.
<br/><br/>
Fatigue battles with rage in this borrowed body, this borrowed mind. Vision swims. I vaguely recall that there's junk in my system and that I (he?) haven't slept.
<br/><br/>
I mutter, pace for a few moments, unsure of what comes next.
<br/><br/>
A key rattles in the door.
<br/><br/>
It opens.
<br/><br/>
May. Nana May. My sister's namesake, the matriarch of the family, steps through in her motorcycle leathers, helmet under arm. It must already be five thirty.
<br/><br/>
Nana May glances at me, down at her daughter, back to me. Her expression is hard, resolute. She adjusts her grip on her helmet and swings it at my face. I'm too slow to react.
<br/><br/>
It hits hard, shocks me back to myself.
<br/><br/>
Back on the bus, aching pain spread across my face, blood dripping from my nose. 
<br/><br/>
Bodily I'm back where I should be, mentally I'm caught halfway between my present and another's past. Seeing my mother like that, through the eyes of her abuser, sickens me and makes me feel like I've lost her again. 
<br/><br/>
The bus rolls to a stop. The doors open. A man in a brown raincoat steps on, the same man I saw at the bus stop near my birth-father's house, the same man who drew the spiral in our window back in Cambridge. I know it's the same man now. He smiles at me, advances towards me, whistling tunelessly.
<br/><br/>
'Mind if I sit here?' he asks, gesturing at the empty seat next to me. I glance up and down the bus. No other passengers, just me and him. 
<br/><br/>
I don't answer. 
<br/><br/>
He sits anyway.
<br/><br/>
The bus sets off, rumbling its way along a street I don't recognise.
<br/><br/>
The man leans towards me. 'It's been a bit of a thrill watching your progress. I didn't think it'd work, you know. Very few of us thought it would. And yet, here we are,' he says. He examines my face, paying particular attention to my eyes. 'We're not quite there, are we? Still, two instances of memory survival! That's pretty good going, Owen. Pretty good indeed.'
<br/><br/>
'Who the fuck are you?'
<br/><br/>
    'I think you know. If not now, you'll remember soon.' He stands, pats my shoulder, and heads for the front of the bus. It rolls to a stop and releases him onto the pavement. Within a second we're moving again.]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nos Da, Tad - Chapter 3</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/serials/nos-da-tad/chapter-3.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
It's well past sunset when we sidle up to the hotel. We'd booked three nights, I wanted one but Martin was sure we'd need a good few days to deal with the house. Martin parks up, we grab our bags from the back, we head in. A touch screen automated check-in service spares us from having to speak to anyone. There's little less appealing right now than the thought of having to wander, machine-like, through the tedious hospitality script with someone who isn't paid enough to give a shit. 
<br/><br/>
The room's small but functional. Twin beds. We shove them together and I sit at the desk while Martin undresses and ducks into the ensuite for a shower. I pull out the unreadable book and the odd tin box, place them on the desk. I rest my chin in my hands and stare at the two objects, those artefacts of a dead king. That's what he was, in his way. A monarch in his own mind, not bound by the laws of lesser folk, burdened with the cruel fate of being born working class and in the twentieth century when he should have been occupying a Renaissance-era palace and surrounded by courtiers, servants, sycophants of every variety. Instead he was in the modern world, running club nights for students and using his powders and potions to seduce the clientele.
<br/><br/>
That's how he'd met my mother. Given her some top-shelf ecstasy at a gig when she was twenty. He'd been young then too, twenty-four. Thirty years later and his target audience hadn't changed, nor had his methods.
<br/><br/>
Why do I know that?
<br/><br/>
Do I know that, or is it an assumption?
<br/><br/>
My mind feels clogged, uncomfortably tight. The gears aren't turning the way they should, something's caught in the mechanism.
<br/><br/>
I stand and wander over to the window, pull a curtain to one side and look out at the car park. Devoid of human life, except for one figure in a long dark coat, standing with the light behind him. Is it the same guy from the bus stop? The same guy from the window? Even if not, I'm certain I've seen that man before. He's not doing anything threatening, of course. Just standing there, waiting for a taxi perhaps. Probably it. Can't just think the worst of people.
<br/><br/>
The shower ceases its hissing. A few minutes later Martin delicately opens the door. I pretend not to notice, watch the moon. He sneaks up behind me and wraps his arms around my midsection. I smile and lean my head back. He kisses my cheek twice. His skin is soft, moisturised, hairless. He rarely shaves, usually just clippers his unruly fuzz down to vaguely presentable stubble. My smile widens and I turn in his arms, wrap mine around his neck. There's a towel wrapped around him and nothing else. He's cautious, slow, respectful of how difficult I've found today. It's sweet, but unnecessary.
<br/><br/>
I kiss him forcefully and walk us both towards the bed. I tug the half-hearted knot at his waist and the towel drops. He pulls my tee-shirt over my head and sits on the edge of the bed, peppering my chest with kisses while he runs his hands from the top of my arse down the back of my thighs, then back up the front to undo my belt. He makes quick work of undoing my jeans, pulls them off along with the boxer shorts beneath. I push him back to a lying position and crawl on top of him. I kiss his neck and caress his abdomen, explore the delicate valleys between peaks of Crossfit musculature.
<br/><br/>
My hand slowly wanders further south. Martin chuckles, runs his fingers through my beard, locks eyes with me. 'I love you,' he says. 
<br/><br/>
I grin broadly and say, 'I love you too.'
<br/><br/>
And then lightning strikes my brain. There's a flash, a hammer strike to the core of my self.
<br/><br/>
The sudden pain starts in my skull, the center of my brain, and in a fraction of a second works its way to every nerve ending. I lose focus, lose sense of who I am, where I am, what's happening.
<br/><br/>
Then the smell hits me. Sour rot, astringent miasma. I'm dressed, standing in a wallpapered room with a 1990 calendar on the wall, holding a polaroid camera. On a table next to me is the lock box from my father's bedroom. I know it's the same one even though it's new and unscathed. It's open and filled with photos face-down.
<br/><br/>
On the bed across the room a young girl, no more than thirteen, fumbles with the buttons of her school uniform shirt. She looks at me, smiles weakly with hollow eyes. 'Owen,' she says weakly.
<br/><br/>
'Owen?!' Martin calls.
<br/><br/>
He lightly slaps my cheek. 
<br/><br/>
I'm laying on my back, on the floor. 
<br/><br/>
He's crouched beside me. 
<br/><br/>
There's panic on his face, a film of greasy sweat on mine.
<br/><br/>
'Oh, thank Christ, you're okay, Fin,' Martin says and pulls me into a fierce hug.
<br/><br/>
I'm stunned. Unsure of what just happened. I was there. It was a memory, from before I was born. My birth father's memory. I know it, as surely as I know I'm 5'8", as surely as I know my birth father was 5'4", as surely as I know we have the same eyes.
<br/><br/>
My eyes drift to that lock box, sitting on the hotel room desk, cloaked in faux honesty. I struggle to my feet with Martin's help. I approach the desk, park myself on the chair.
<br/><br/>
'What's going on?' Martin asks.
<br/><br/>
I reach for the box. It's not locked anymore, not for me. My hands shake. I place them both on the lid, ease it open. Hold it there, not closed but nowhere near open enough to reveal the contents. 
<br/><br/>
'What the fuck,'Martin breathes, shaking his head.
<br/><br/>
I feel a twinge of guilt for not responding, but my focus cannot not be interrupted right now. I inhale, fill my lungs with recycled air and a hint of my own odour. Fuck, I'm a mess.
<br/><br/>
Enough dicking around. I flip the lid open, glance at the contents.
<br/><br/>
Polaroids. Dozens, if I'm any judge. I can't bring myself to look through them and Martin covers his eyes with one hand, the other on his hip, inventive curses on his lips. So, really, we don't know if they're all as bad as the few that are visible on the top. They're bad enough though.
<br/><br/>
Young girls, early teens, undressed. Not always alone. He's in some of the pictures. That's the first time I've seen my birth-father's face.]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nos Da, Tad - Chapter 2</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/serials/nos-da-tad/chapter-2.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
The drive is almost three hours. It starts off pretty pleasant, lots of good music and worthwhile conversation. That all winds down as we draw closer to the no-name town my father has been haunting for the last thirty years. I text May, my half-sister, en route. Fill her in on the situation. That does little for my mood. By the time we cross into the town itself we're entirely silent. 'Welcome to Ferenbrooke' says the sign, nondescript white letters on a generic green background. All evidence thus far suggests an entirely average town with rather special aspirations.
<br/><br/>
My birth-father's house sits towards the outskirts of town, in a sparsely populated road just by the motorway. The properties here look to have been built post-war, quickly, and cheaply. Probably council housing or some other social housing scheme, at least initially. Every house on the street is of roughly the same construction, semi-detached two-beds in red brick with very little outside space. 
<br/><br/>
Martin smoothly guides his Volkswagen, dodges a motley collection of rusted and uncared-for cars along the decayed road, more filled holes than original tarmac, passes the world's least inspiring bus stop and its raincoat-clad occupant, who reminds me of the man who drew on our window. I eye him as we drive past, waiting for him to raise his head and see our car, but he remains still. I mentally chide myself for my paranoia and examine the house numbers.
<br/><br/>
'We're looking for 43,' I say.
<br/><br/>
'Yeah, I remember. That'll be it, just before the corner.'
<br/><br/>
That's the destination alright, another bland house with a messy lawn and filthy windows. An elderly man stands by the door, watching us approach. He's short, skinny, has a bulbous nose and bright eyes reminiscent of my own. My heart skips a beat. Of course, it's not my father. He's dead. But it could definitely be his brother, the man on the phone. I had called him back after speaking to Martin, arranged this visit. During that call, Donald told me that my father died from a drug overdose. Seems fitting, banal even.
<br/><br/>
Martin turns his head and fixes me with those big brown eyes, lets out a long slow breath. 
<br/><br/>
'You ready?' he asks.
<br/><br/>
I nod. The nod is a lie and Martin's expression tells me that he clearly knows it is, but he accepts it anyway and opens his door. The old man approaches Martin with a hand extended, they shake hands and exchange forced smiles while I drag myself from the passenger seat and slowly amble around the car to the fractured footpath. Christ, this part of town is a shit-hole. Probably why my father felt so at home here.
<br/><br/>
'Donald Wood,' the old man says, 'Owen Wood's older brother. You must be Martin?'
<br/><br/>
'That's what they tell me,' Martin replies, wearing half a smile. 
<br/><br/>
I approach tentatively. In theory, this is going quite well. Donald appears to have no issue whatsoever with my partner being a Black man, he's polite, seems to want nothing from me that I'm not willing to offer freely. So why does this feel so wrong? There's a sense of distance, of my core self withdrawing. The world feels ephemeral, transient. The cracked paving beneath my feet shifts with my steps, rocking back and forth just enough to conjure the thought that perhaps there's nothing beneath at all, that the ground we walk upon extends only inches down, that the material reality in which we live and breathe and fuck and die is merely a facade. Perhaps I am too.
<br/><br/>
Donald turns to me and smiles. He holds out a wrinkled little paw. I grasp it, because that's what you're supposed to do. I shake it.
<br/><br/>
My birth-father's brother claps me on the upper arm with his free hand, still gripping my right with his. 'Owen,' he says, eyes moist, chin quivering, 'I've hoped to meet you for so very long. You look just like him, you know. In the face, I mean. The way you hold yourself, the way you walk, that's very different.'
<br/><br/>
If I were more present I might visibly recoil at the idea I bear so much resemblance to my mother's abuser. As things are, I nod and smile in my best estimation of a polite manner.
<br/><br/>
'Nice to meet you.' I mumble. Our hands separate. I wasn't sure they ever would. My sense of self starts to reassert. The world returns to solidity by degrees.
<br/><br/>
'So, shall we take a look inside?'
<br/><br/>
Martin steps forward, glances at me with a soft look in his eyes. 'Ah, I don't want to come off as rude, Donald, but I think this would be easier on Owen if it were just the two of us today.'
<br/><br/>
Donald's eyebrows attempt lift-off. 'Oh, right, yes. I understand.' He smiles at Martin and then at me. He reaches into the inside pocket of his tweed jacket and pulls out a slightly rusted ring holding several keys. 'It's the big one for the front door,' he says. He pats me on the arm again, drops the keys into my hand, and nods cordially to Martin before walking north towards a bus stop at the end of the road, head bowed.
<br/><br/>
Martin softly punches my shoulder. I sigh, nod, and turn to face Donald.
<br/><br/>
'Hey, Donald, I'll call you later. We should all grab lunch or somethin' before Martin and I head back to Cambridgeshire.'
<br/><br/>
The old man half jumps at the sound of his name. He looks back over his shoulder, offers a quivering smile and says, 'That sounds lovely.'
<br/><br/>
With that said he progresses farther up the road and Martin and I turn to face each other.
<br/><br/>
'You ready?' he asks.
<br/><br/>
'Let's do it,' I say. I open my hand and examine the keys I received from Donald. Four of them, one of the old style brass Mortice type, three of the flat sort. A deep breath, a moment to clear my mind, and we're walking up the path to the front door. It's the white plastic kind you often see on social housing; cheap and easy to maintain. Nonetheless this one has acquired a fair bit of wear and tear. Discolouration particularly. Christ, how do you even produce that shade of piss yellow? Piss, obviously, but how and why? Could it be intentional? Some fucking bizarre fashion statement, or merely a reflection of the owner's character?
<br/><br/>
'We gonna stare at that door all day?'
<br/><br/>
I glance at Martin. 'Sorry,' I say. I select the largest of the three flat keys and slot it into the lock on the front door. It opens easily enough. In I go. The hairs on the back of my neck stand up, I shiver.
<br/><br/>
The hallway stinks. Old smoke and older dust. Stairs leading up, presumably to bedrooms. We can check those out last. To my left is a doorway, half open. I peek in while Martin enters the house behind me and shuts the door.
<br/><br/>
A threadbare sofa sits right in the centre. There's an old TV with a cracked screen in the far corner, by the window. The curtains are moldy. There's a coffee table, of sorts, with the faint remains of various herbs and powders ground into the crevices. Behind the sofa, a bookshelf. I walk over and examine the selection. Mostly non-fiction, some thrillers, a little horror. I select a book at random and pull it out to look at the cover. Splinter and Other Stories by Alex Wolfgang. It looks creepy. There's a bookmark in there. I open it to the marked page and read a few paragraphs from a short story called Mandibles then return the book to the shelf, bile rising in my throat. Disgusting.
<br/><br/>
One of the shelves is filled with science publications, focusing on biology. The book The Epigenetics Revolution is heavily marked, well handled. I don't bother thumbing through; that stuff's too dry for me.
<br/><br/>
I feel Martin's hand on my back. 'I guess we should see the other rooms,' I say.
<br/><br/>
'Huh?' Martin responds from far away.
<br/><br/>
I turn around. He's not there. Nobody is. I poke my head back into the hallway and see him further down, examining the fridge in a pokey little galley kitchen.
<br/><br/>
'You call me?' he asks.
<br/><br/>
'Sorry, I thought you were in there with me.'
<br/><br/>
'Did you want me to be? I'm sorry, I thought I'd scout ahead and make sure there was nothing too traumatic in here. Luckily someone cleaned out the fridge. Either that, or the fucker didn't eat.' 
<br/><br/>
I look into the pristine chamber, a tiny white box furnished for dead things waiting to be consumed, chill, lifeless. It's far and away the cleanest part of the house I've seen. I cast my eye around the rest of the kitchen, examine every detail like a detective in some shitty American drama. The oven is filthy, crusted with the particular form of detritus common to appliances left fallow. A microwave on the work surface by the sink seems to have seen more use. The sink itself is stainless steel and spotless. A washing machine and dryer sit side by side, occupying the space under the work surface. 
<br/><br/>
At the farthest end of the galley kitchen from the front of the house, a doorway opens into a tight little bathroom. It's in good repair, the shower-over-bath arrangement appears to be a recent addition. I suspect that my birth-father took some pride in his appearance. I imagine him in there, water cascading down that face, utterly unknown to me yet so familiar to anyone who has seen my own. Did he ever think of me? As hot water poured over him, rinsing the taint of his perversions from his degraded, amphetamine fuelled body, the eager hiss of the shower head emptying his head of daily trivialities, did his mind ever wander to that half-formed family he left behind in Cambridgeshire? Did the son who bears his name, his blood, a facsimile of his features, ever intrude upon the ill-gotten tranquility in his head and his home?
<br/><br/>
I doubt it.
<br/><br/>
It occurs to me that I've been staring at the shower for quite some time. I turn and see Martin staring at me, head slightly inclined, a patient smile on his lips and concern in his eyes. I wrap my arms around him and bury my face in his neck, moisten his collar with tears I'm surprised to see. He rubs my back and rocks me from side to side, slowly, gently.
<br/><br/>
'Let's check out the bedrooms, finish getting the lay of the land, then head to the hotel. We can deal with things properly tomorrow,' I say.
<br/><br/>
'Sounds good,' Martin says.
<br/><br/>
With his hand in mine I lead him to the stairs, half pull him up. He's reticent. I look back and raise one eyebrow.
<br/><br/>
He wears a concerned expression, looks past me at the top of the stairs. 'Something doesn't feel right.'
<br/><br/>
'You're not wrong there, the whole house has it, right? That atmosphere, that chill.'
<br/><br/>
'It's like when we went down that iron-age mine, you remember?'
<br/><br/>
'Yeah,' I say. He's so very right. The coldness, it has nothing to do with thermodynamics. It's not an absence of heat, at least not just that. It's an absence of the essential vitality that flows through every environment capable of supporting life. It's like the void of space.
<br/><br/>
I take a deep breath. The air is foetid. 'Let's get this over with,' I say.
<br/><br/>
At the top of the stairs, another bookcase. This one is loaded with CDs. Who has CDs these days? There's R&B, drum & bass, jungle, garage, a little '80s hair metal. Nothing good.
<br/><br/>
Two doors, both ajar. We nudge open the left door first. Double bed, wardrobe, chest of drawers. All cheap flat-pack stuff. Bed sheets and blankets look unwashed in the extreme. There's a stench in here, old sweat and stale cigarette smoke.
<br/><br/>
On top of the chest of drawers there's a lock box, one of the tin ones that market traders often use for petty cash. I pull the keys from my pocket. Nothing that would fit.
<br/><br/>
But I need to get into that box.
<br/><br/>
I lift the box and show it to Martin. 'You see a key for this anywhere?' I ask.
<br/><br/>
He shakes his head then walks past me and starts opening drawers, I check the wardrobe. Ratty clothes, mainly jeans and band tee-shirts. Christ, how old was this guy? His brother's pushing seventy.
<br/><br/>
Fifty-five. He was fifty-five.
<br/><br/>
Why do I know that? 
<br/><br/>
Mum told me when I was a kid and I don't consciously remember. That must be it.
<br/><br/>
'There could be a key somewhere in the other room,' Martin says. He gestures at the box. 'What do you think is in there?'
<br/><br/>
I glance at him then look down at the box, hold it up. It's old, older than I am I think. 'I don't know. I want to know though, I feel like I need to know.'
<br/><br/>
Martin nods. He lays a hand on my shoulder and smiles, soft eyes fixed on mine.
<br/><br/>
His patience astounds me. His compassion is almost more than I can take. I don't know how I'd cope without him here.
<br/><br/>
We move as one towards the final door. I raise a hand as if to knock. I don't know why. I glance at Martin, he's suppressing a laugh in a manner that falls some distance short of being convincing. I grunt and place my palm upon the old oak.
<br/><br/>
It's freezing. 
<br/><br/>
I furrow my brow and push the door open.
<br/><br/>
Immediately my eyes drift around the room, searching for the source of the preternatural chill. Nothing. It's a small box room, three walls lined with shelves, each occupied by odd books and jars. A desk sits by the window, blackout curtains block any trace of sunlight. I flick the lightswitch and step in. Martin follows and approaches a shelf, focuses on a jar, picks it up, examines the contents.
<br/><br/>
'This looks like mud or something,' he says, 'there's a handwritten label, in funny squiggly letters.'
<br/><br/>
I join him. 'Is that Hebrew, or Arabic, something like that?'
<br/><br/>
Martin shakes his head. 'Kinda looks a bit like Thai, but fucked up.'
<br/><br/>
Every other container I check is labelled in a similar oblique fashion. I take a book from the top shelf. It's a journal, a spiral drawn on the front, text handwritten in the same script as the jar labels. I flick through. Some diagrams are recognisable as humanoid forms and sections thereof, overlain with geometric patterns and labelled with notes, formulae, strange little symbols. I keep the journal in my hand as I examine a shelf of less opaque texts. Largely textbooks, by the look of it. A lot of biology and genetics and things like that. It seems my birth father was less of an air head than I'd thought.
<br/><br/>
    I close the strange book and raise it in the air. 'I'm gonna take this too, I think.']]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Sound</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/short-stories/the-sound.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[The event was larger than I'd anticipated. Close to a hundred people filled the small University hall, half a dozen or so waitstaff tending to the crowd. Across the other end of the room I saw Chelsea getting balls deep into yet another white wine spritzer. Old stone walls lent the whole affair a grandiose atmosphere and spine-breaking acoustics. Every word became a warcry, every whisper a scream.
<br/><br/>
The main man, Doctor Sullivan Griever himself, occasionally appeared from a dark corner and borrowed the ear of one of his favoured guests: friends from the physics department, sponsors of his research, patrons of his unusual musical experiments.
<br/><br/>
It was an odd thing, the way Sullivan would translate pulses of light from far off nebulae into musical notation and combine it with deep-sea calls from unidentified species. The music of the unreachable places, he called it. Some people liked it, I suppose.
<br/><br/>
Elton sidled up to me, beer in one hand and spectacles in the other. 'What do you think the big reveal will be?' he asked, neatly side-stepping basic pleasantries. I appreciated that about him.
<br/><br/>
'Oh, I don't know. Probably some more of that music he does. I imagine he found a particularly noisy star cluster or a talkative squid, or something.' In truth, I could barely muster the thinnest facade of interest in the event. My attendance was motivated purely by guilt. I'd received a letter the day previous, telling me that Sullivan was on his way out whether he realised it or not, and I'd be replacing him as the head of the astrophysics department. His chief source of funding, a group of old-fashioned would-be gentleman scientists called the Bayemont Society, had chosen to put their cash and influence behind a less frivolous soul. This event would likely be the last hurrah for dear doctor Griever. I just wished he'd hurry the fuck up, frankly. I was missing *Married at First Sight* for the event, and my wife Sarah was likely to be upset at me for days over it.
<br/><br/>
Elton and I were brushed aside as a grad student named Gully Novaro passed, carrying a wooden panel with the help of another young man whose name I believe was TJ---so hard to remember them all now.
<br/><br/>
We slid noiselessly across uneven stones and found a perch by a statue of some significant figure from the 17th century and watched as the two PhD candidates assembled a stage along one of the long sides of the hall. Their movements were slick, practised. I found myself ever more sure of the decision to remove Griever---if he was using students to regularly help him host his events rather than supporting their studies as he should, then he definitely needed to go.
<br/><br/>
Within a few short minutes, the stage was assembled and Doctor Sullivan stepped upon it, the mob of intellectuals around him reaching something close to silence by unspoken consensus.
<br/><br/>
The Doctor cleared his throat and spoke, a frantic ripple in his voice. 'Guests, friends, colleagues. Thank you for coming!' he said. Behind him, the PhD candidates set up an array of arcane speakers, odd vintage things with tubes and wood panelling. Sullivan continued, 'as many of you know, I have a little side project, informed by my work in the astrophysics department. Today, I present to you my magnum opus!'
<br/><br/>
Elton nudged me and gestured to the doors. I looked, saw that the waitstaff were locking them. I raised an eyebrow and shrugged at my companion.
<br/><br/>
Griever's borderline-raving continued. 'As my colleagues in the department will no doubt be aware, the Bayemont Society have lent us the use of one of their radio telescopes. We recently pointed it at a recently discovered cluster of stars farther away than any we've yet analysed, at the furthest reaches of the spiral arm of our galaxy. My friends, the signal we received has shattered every idea we had about the nature of our universe!'
<br/><br/>
'I think it's time to leave,' I muttered. Elton nodded at the edge of my peripheral vision. Neither of us wanted to watch a man who could, on a good day, be considered our friend collapse into madness. Cosmic pareidolia. Whatever was going on. We moved for the exit, at which stood a particularly sizeable waiter. 'Excuse me, I'll need you to open the door,' I said.
<br/><br/>
The waiter appeared not to notice.
<br/><br/>
Elton and I exchanged glances. Elton's face reflected the twinge of panic I felt. He cleared his throat and turned towards the stage. 'Doctor Griever, why won't they let us out?' he called loudly.
<br/><br/>
Sullivan fixed his blood-shot eyes on us. Or almost. His pupils danced left and right, a nystagmatic motion devoid of lucidity. 'You have to hear it,' he said, almost in a whisper. Then he shouted it. 'YOU HAVE TO HEAR IT! CLEARER THAN WORDS, ELTON!'
<br/><br/>
With that, he stepped backwards and pulled the power lever for the strange set-up his assistants had assembled.
<br/><br/>
For a blessed second, nothing happened.
<br/><br/>
And then, a low hum.
<br/><br/>
It slowly built, slowly grew deep and rhythmically waved. At points in the cycle of frequencies, the wooden furniture in room shook. Then the glass of the windows. And then the stone.
<br/><br/>
Panic spread throughout the mob as centuries-old walls began to shed loose stone. Sullivan stood in the middle of it all, among his strange speakers, arms raised like some twisted interpretation of the crucifixion. The force of the ever-rising sounds behind him buffeted his body, bunched and spread his skin in turn.
<br/><br/>
The sound became unbearable. Windows shattered, the youngest among us collapsed with bleeding ears. I knew I'd follow before long. Elton tapped my shoulder, tried to shout something. Totally inaudible. He pointed at the now-collapsed waiter by the door, which was being pounded on by half a dozen University staffers. He was curled up in the foetal position, cradling his head. I couldn't blame him.
<br/><br/>
Elton crouched next to him, searched his pockets. Within seconds he stood triumphant, holding a huge brass key.
<br/><br/>
The key, of course, shattered. Another victim of whatever blasted frequency tore through us.
<br/><br/>
Wide-eyed, I turned to look at Griever. He was on his knees, mad glee on his face and blood dripping from his eyes, nose, and ears. He reached his hand towards a dial---a dial which proved to be the master volume control when he turned it to its end.
<br/><br/>
It was unbearable. I felt my eardrums tear, watched the world shae out of control. Was it the building itself? My eyes? Both?
<br/><br/>
I collapsed to the ground. Next to me, Elton crumpled. He foamed at the mouth and spasmed on the floor. All around me, similar scenes occured. Limbs shook hard enough to break the bones within, walls collapsed and crushed mewling academics with man-sized fragments of stone.
<br/><br/>
It might have been seconds or hours before the power---and thus the sound---went out. By that point, I'd lost touch with the world. I saw nothing, felt nothing, heard only the sound.
<br/><br/>
Even now, it's all I hear. Seven of us survived, the others hear it too. Griever, for all his madness, was right. It *is* clearer than words, once the rest of the noise fades away and leaves you only with the music of the unreachable places.
<br/><br/>
    It doesn't just speak, it sings. Whatever it is in that far away cluster of stars, it has a message. Sullivan tried to deliver it. He came close. Now, I sit here, devoid of auditory distractions, and hold in my hands the letter from the Bayemont society promising me the means to finish the job.]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nos Da, Tad - Chapter 1</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/serials/nos-da-tad/chapter-1.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA['Your father is dead.'
<br/><br/>
'Okay,' I say into the phone. I pinch a lock of my hair with two fingers of my free hand and pull it flat against my forehead. It's almost long enough to hide my eyebrows. I should book in for a trim.
<br/><br/>
The voice, a withered little thing belonging to a fragile little man, umms and ahhs in my ear.
<br/><br/>
'Was there something else?' I ask. 
<br/><br/>
'Owen, are you going to be alright? Do I need to call someone for you?'
<br/><br/>
It occurs to me that the man talking to me is Welsh. Of course, he would be, given that he's apparently my birth-father's brother and my birth-father is reportedly from Wales.
<br/><br/>
'I'm fine. Seriously. I never even met the guy. As far as I knew, he was already dead.'
<br/><br/>
'Yes, well. I am sorry for that. Truly. I'd have gotten in contact with you much sooner, if it were up to me. Your father was insistent that you be left alone. I understand he and your mother didn't part under the best of terms.'
<br/><br/>
'You could say that.' I notice his reticence to name my father. Owen. We share that, if nothing else. He made sure of that, waited for the ink to dry on the birth certificate before he made his escape. It used to bother me, when I was a kid. Now I'm pushing thirty and it only crosses my mind a few times a day. 
<br/><br/>
A pause. 'There's one more thing, actually.'
<br/><br/>
'Yeah?' I lean back in my chair, put my feet up on the kitchen table. Glance at the digital clock on the oven, eleven AM. I hope this doesn't take too long, I promised Martin I'd get the dishes done before he came home and I'm theoretically working from home. I'll have to get a few invoices sent off this afternoon if I don't want a bollocking from the head of accounts.
<br/><br/>
'The will,' he says, his voice timid. 
<br/><br/>
Heat rushes to my cheeks. 'I don't need his crack pipe,' I say, trying in vain to keep the indignation from my voice. I return my feet to the floor and reach for my cigarettes. I light one and pull the ashtray towards myself.
<br/><br/>
'It's not just that. As flawed as he was, my brother had some talent with money. He left you everything, including his house.'
<br/><br/>
At this my eyebrows raise. From what I've heard my father was a mediocre, at best, club DJ who mooched off everyone he'd ever known. Sold pills and herb to keep himself more or less liquid. How does someone like that end up owning a house?
<br/><br/>
We speak a little longer. He agrees to send me the paperwork. I just want to sell the place and burn the contents; sadly the law requires an exorbitant level of paperwork before I can light the match. 
<br/><br/>
The conversation ends cordially enough. I stand, light another cigarette and start pacing around the flat. I do little laps, starting at the kitchen table and going up to the oven before turning and making my way to the sitting room. Circle the couch, back to the kitchen table, repeat. Every conversation I'd ever imagined having with my birth-father runs through my mind. I mouth my side silently and pause for the imagined responses. Light my next cigarette off the butt of the current one. Keep pacing, keep mumbling, wipe the tears from my eyes as soon as they appear, jump out of my skin when I hear a key turn in the front door lock.
<br/><br/>
When did it get dark?
<br/><br/>
No matter. I turn to face the door, force a smile and greet my boyfriend as though it's any other day. 
<br/><br/>
Martin takes one look at my face and drops his rucksack just inside the door then rushes over, wrapping his arms around me. He lets the door slowly swing shut on its own. 'Are you okay? What's wrong?' he asks.
<br/><br/>
'It's been a hell of a week.'
<br/><br/>
'It's Monday.'
<br/><br/>
I smile and lead him to the kitchen table. We sit, him on the end and me along the side opposite the wall. One of my knees touches one of his, a third point of contact along with our intertwined hands. That's good. I need to suck every spare bit of warmth from him, every ounce of comfort, every glimmer of compassion.
<br/><br/>
'Got a phone call. Some guy called Donald Wood, says he's my uncle. My birth father is dead. And there's a will, apparently I'm getting a house and some other shit.'
<br/><br/>
Martin's brow furrows. He tuts quietly and moves his left hand to my cheek. I lean into it.
<br/><br/>
'I'm so sorry, Fin. I know you had a lot you wanted to say to him,' he says. His voice is warm and liquid. His thumb lays at the corner of my lips. I kiss it. I love it when he uses that dumb nickname. Fin, because we met diving.
<br/><br/>
I exhale slowly. 'Yeah, well, too late now.'
<br/><br/>
Martin nods. He half-stands and leans towards me, wrapping his arms around my shoulders. He holds me like that, breathes onto my neck and rubs my back with one of his huge hands, gently but with conviction. Eventually he stands up fully and says, 'So what do you want to do? About the inheritance?'
<br/><br/>
I shrug. 'House could be worth a few quid. We should check it out.'
<br/><br/>
'We can burn everything inside, if you want.'
<br/><br/>
I smile. 'Great idea.'
<br/><br/>
Martin rises from his chair, steps over to the kitchen counter. 'I'll put the kettle on. You lay on the sofa, put your feet up. This is no time for good sitting posture.'
<br/><br/>
I nod and lurch in Frankenstein-esque fashion towards the two-seater that dominates the lounge, tattered and grey and thick with an excess of padding and a surplus of memories. 
<br/><br/>
I plant myself down and swivel to stretch my legs out on the familiar fabric. For a moment I'm silent and still, then restlessness sets in and I turn my head to look out the window. I see a man in a brown raincoat walk past and glance in at us. He stops at our window, blows onto it and draws a spiral into the condensation before marching off quickly. A shiver runs up my spine and I call for Martin.
<br/><br/>
He rushes into the room. 'What's up?'
<br/><br/>
'Some weird guy was at the window.' I point to the quickly fading mark on our window. 'He left that.'
<br/><br/>
Martin shook his head. 'People, man. Bunch of freaks.'
<br/><br/>
I nod. There's a chill in the room so I pull the throw from the back of the sofa and drape it over myself, pull my legs up and hug them to me. Martin sits on the vacated spot beside me and rubs my knee.
<br/><br/>
'You're going to be okay, you know that right? Shit might get a little weird, but I'll be there. You aren't alone.' He speaks slowly, softly.
<br/><br/>
    'Yeah, of course.' I smile and nod towards the kitchen as the kettle boils and clicks.]]>
</description>
</item>
		<item>
			<title>Returning to Writing</title>
			<link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/blog/returning-to-writing.html</link>
			<description>
                <![CDATA[05/11/2014
                <br/><br/>
                    It's been a long time since I've written creatively.
                <br/><br/>
I've done a few blog posts about tech and politics on my other blog, but I haven't made stories in quite a while. I've really missed it. I wish I could have come back sooner, but things have been a tad crazy. I had a kid and then I almost died. It's all very dramatic, but that's not what I'm here to write about.
                <br/><br/>
I'm genuinely excited by this little project. Serials and shorts written for pure fun, in my own weird little world. I have no idea if anyone will read it and I find myself not worrying much about it. It's a nice place to be as a hobbyist writer, really. I'm not sure if I'll do the whole submission grind thing later down the line, but for now having my own little corner of the internet where the only person I'm trying to please is me feels like the smart move.
                <br/><br/>
I'll keep this first entry short and sweet, end it here.
                <br/><br/>
Thanks for reading.
                <br/><br/>
                    -Antony]]> 
</description>
		<pubDate>Tues, November 5 2024</pubDate>
	</item>
        <item>
            <title>The Landlord</title>
            <link>https://www.ferenbrooke.com/short-stories/the-landlord.html</link>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[Lucy Hayward placed her mug down on her kitchen table, furrowed her
brow, and said, 'You're actually gonna do it?'
<br/><br/>
Chris O'Halloran, a good-natured Canadian from the flat across the
hallway, shrugged and said, 'Yeah, why not? He's paying.' He was sitting
on the other end of her sofa, sipping water, doing the neighbourly thing
and giving her the lay of the land.
<br/><br/>
Lucy shuddered. 'Albert's creepy as fuck,' she said.
<br/><br/>
She'd only moved in a few weeks previous and still held visceral
memories of his unsettling demeanour. It was an odd set-up, an acre of
land on the outskirts of Ferenbrooke with two houses upon it. One of the
buildings, post-war and generally bleak, became the block in which Lucy
and Chris, among others, lived. Albert occupied the older, grander,
red-brick Victorian house.
<br/><br/>
'He's a sculptor, an artist, they have to be a little off. It's the
law.'
<br/><br/>
Lucy smiled at this. 'How long does it take, modelling for a bust?'
<br/><br/>
'I said I'd give him two hours, and come back again if that wasn't
enough,' Chris said. He drained the last of his water and stood,
stretching. 'Thanks for the hospitality. Like I said, any questions you
give me a call.'
<br/><br/>
Lucy stood and walked him to the door. 'I will. And if you're not back
in two hours I'll send a search party.'
<br/><br/>
\#
<br/><br/>
Lucy sat alone in her top-floor flat and worried. Chris had been at
Albert's house for four hours at least. She occupied her usual perch,
the ledge under the window, opened a crack, with a hefty glass of
Tempranillo and a family pack of digestive biscuits. Her gaze flitted
back and forth between the front door and the rearmost window on the
ground floor of the landlord's house, clearly visible from her high
vantage point. She'd quickly figured out that said window belonged to
Albert's sculpting workshop; though the glass was frosted as one would
expect in a bathroom, he occasionally opened it an inch or two. A keen
eye could glimpse a table occupied by myriad tools and a stout wooden
chair flecked with grey clay. A keen eye with the aid of binoculars,
that is.
<br/><br/>
She couldn't shake the feeling that something was untoward. Was it
normal for landlords with creative hobbies to ask their tenants to
participate? To model for them? It made her uncomfortable in the
extreme.
<br/><br/>
Lucy pictured Albert's gnarled rat-paw hands forming and shaping and
reshaping Chris' head without tools, driving his yellow talon-like
fingernails into the eye sockets to form pupils. She shuddered, shook
her head involuntarily.
<br/><br/>
The wind was picking up. Faint howls of impatient air forced their way
through pine branches and past red brick walls, carrying earthy, herbal
chrysanthemum to Lucy's nose. She closed the window, conscious of the
chill in the air. The sky had darkened to the deep blue of her own
wine-stained lips, the glorious half-moon hovering above her landlord's
house, eagerly awaiting the arrival of its companion stars.
<br/><br/>
She spotted Chris, staggering up the pathway between Albert's front door
and their own. She squinted and rested her forehead on the glass, trying
to identify what was wrong with him. He looked pallid, grey almost, and
moved in a stiff manner. Lucy's jaw tightened; he seemed hurt, or unwell
in some way. She stood, left her wine glass and biscuits on the window
ledge and headed for the door.
<br/><br/>
Their paths met in the hallway, one floor below. Lucy's breath abandoned
her when she saw Chris. He was vacant-eyed. One hand supported him
against the wall while the other held a black scarf tight around his
neck.
<br/><br/>
'Hey, what's wrong?' she asked, trying to prevent any trace of the panic
she felt from entering her voice.
<br/><br/>
His eyes swivelled in his head and rested on her. He smiled sheepishly.
'Bed,' he said.
<br/><br/>
Lucy put an arm around him, took some of his weight. She helped him
climb the stairs and got him to his front door, where he fumbled with
his keys, dropping them. She retrieved them from the floor and unlocked
his door.
<br/><br/>
Chris stamped through his doorway and turned back to face her, stared
unblinking for a long moment, a stiff grin on his face. She met his
gaze, intended to speak, but couldn't summon any words to fill the
torturous silence.
<br/><br/>
With tears in her eyes, Lucy backed out of Chris' flat and shut the
door.
<br/><br/>
\#
<br/><br/>
The next morning, Lucy knocked on Chris' door.
<br/><br/>
No answer.
<br/><br/>
She walked the path to her landlord's door. The clay heads -- treated,
according to Albert, with a chemical process of his own design which
allowed them to survive outside -- lining the path were very impressive
up close; one could almost think the eyes were fixed on a person as they
passed, following each visitor for a moment before the grey faces
settled back into the repose of the never-living.
<br/><br/>
She cast a glance over her shoulder, regarded the serpentine route
she\'d just travelled. One of the watchful grey faces caught her eye. It
was different from the others, the clavicles of the bust faced forwards
as with the others but it turned at the neck to face the doorway of the
house where she now stood. It had a forlorn expression and its eyes
seemed fixed on her. She hadn\'t noticed it being that way when she\'d
passed it mere moments before. She kept her left hand in the deep pocket
of her long cardigan, which also contained an illicitly procured
miniature spray can of mace, and hammered Albert's door with her right.
<br/><br/>
Albert opened the door eventually. 'Good morning, Miss Hayward. What can
I do for you?' He spoke with a clarity and focus not typical of
men-of-leisure on crisp autumn mornings. He was a shortish, slight man,
pale and dark haired. He had an odd waxen quality to his face, could
have been anywhere from forty-five to sixty-five years old. He
absent-mindedly brushed fictional dust from a cashmere-clad shoulder and
quirked an eyebrow at Lucy.
<br/><br/>
'I was wondering, could I speak to you about Chris? Chris O'Halloran,
from the apartment next to mine? I'm worried about him.'
<br/><br/>
Alberts raised an eyebrow slightly. 'Please, come in.'
<br/><br/>
Lucy followed him into his home. They proceeded past two doors on the
right: the one to the study in which she'd signed her tenancy agreement,
and another which had a brass nameplate inscribed with 'Office &
Workshop'. Through that door would be the other side of the rearmost
window. After these, Albert stopped by a door on the left. He held it
open and waved Lucy through. She smiled faintly and nodded her thanks,
right hand on her mace within her voluminous right pocket.
<br/><br/>
It was a sitting room -- well, it'd more properly be referred to as a
drawing room in this sort of house, Lucy mused to herself -- decorated
in a lavish style reminiscent of the 1920s. The wood panelling on the
walls was painted a sombre greyish blue, three sofas formed a 'U' around
a broad oak coffee table in front of a fireplace, and the carpet was
thick and lush; so much so that Lucy felt a pang of guilt for wearing
her shoes inside.
<br/><br/>
Albert sat on the sofa opposite the fireplace, motioned for Lucy to sit
upon the one to the right. That would leave her back to the door. While
not keen on the idea, she didn't see much value in arguing, and so
followed his direction.
<br/><br/>
'So,' the landlord said, tapping his knees, 'How can I help?'
<br/><br/>
'I'm worried about Chris. He seemed so out of it when I saw him last
night, after leaving here. Like he was, I dunno, sick or something.'
<br/><br/>
Albert nodded. 'We had a couple of drinks after our session. You're
aware that I'm using him as a subject for my work?'
<br/><br/>
Lucy nodded. Smiled, insincerely. There had been no smell of alcohol on
Chris. And even if there had been, his demeanour wasn't that of a drunk.
<br/><br/>
Albert cleared his throat and continued, 'I'm sure he won't mind me
telling you this, he's also been using me to unload, so to speak. He has
a lot of anxiety. I won't go into specifics, but like many rudderless
young men he appreciates a...more seasoned ear. I like to think my true
purpose in life is not merely to recreate human heads through sculpture,
but to help mould the contents of them through wise guidance.'
<br/><br/>
'You're like Chris' counsellor?'
<br/><br/>
'Like a mentor, or a friend perhaps. I could be that for you too, you
know.'
<br/><br/>
She shook her head. 'I'm fine, thanks.'
<br/><br/>
'Your references from your last landlord suggest not,' he said, a hint
of toxic glee in his voice.
<br/><br/>
Lucy's eyes widened. She stuttered, wanting to say something but unable
to produce anything worth saying.
<br/><br/>
Albert smiled warmly, leant forwards in his chair, and steepled his
fingers while resting elbows on knees. 'Yes, that's right. You were
caught picking the lock on your housemate's door. You told her you
suspected her of some sordid crime or another, yes?'
<br/><br/>
Lucy swallowed. She said, 'Look, I was going through a bad time. My
thoughts...got away from me for a minute.'
<br/><br/>
'What thoughts were these, that got away from you?' Albert's cold eyes
bored into Lucy, rooted her in place.
<br/><br/>
'There had been a couple of home invasions. Witnesses said it was a
couple, a man and a woman. Killing whole families. Jenny and her
boyfriend fitted the descriptions. And you never know, you know?' she
paused, took a breath. She couldn't pull her eyes from his, couldn't
keep her mouth shut. She continued, 'I was obsessed, paranoid. I admit
it. But I'm fine now.'
<br/><br/>
'Paranoia isn't fine, and it doesn't go away on its own. I might be able
to help. It can be quite soothing, talking through your troubles while I
make you a head,' Albert said, breaking eye contact and nodding in the
direction of a woman's bust mounted above the fireplace.
<br/><br/>
Spell broken, Lucy glanced at the bust. Young, pretty, she thought. She
fancied she saw terror in those blank clay eyes.
<br/><br/>
Bile rose in her throat. 'Like you're helping Chris? He didn't seem to
be benefitting much last night.'
<br/><br/>
'Change is hard. Letting go of wild impulses, settling into a simpler
mindset of service and selflessness, it takes work. I'm sure he'd say
it's worth it, though. He's here now, actually. I think he might stay a
little while, considering the circumstances. Would you like to see him?'
<br/><br/>
As if on cue, the door behind Lucy's seat began to creak. She shot to
her feet and turned to face it, meeting Chris' vacant gaze as he
entered.
<br/><br/>
'Hi Lucy,' Chris said. He waved enthusiastically, a dumb grin on his
face, like a huge medicated toddler.
<br/><br/>
Lucy smiled at him then shot a look at Albert, who'd leant back into his
chosen sofa, arms splayed out across the back. She said, 'Well, since
we're all good here, I'll be off.'
<br/><br/>
'Of course, don't let us keep you,' said the Landlord, 'and do think on
my offer, won't you?'
<br/><br/>
'I will,' she said. She passed Chris, briefly giving him a one-armed
half-hug on the way and whispering, 'See you soon.' Within moments she
was back outside and halfway up the path. She paused a moment, turned
back and looked up at the landlord's house. Even in daylight it seemed
bathed in darkness. She knew she'd have to come back, figure out what
was going on.
<br/><br/>
\#
<br/><br/>
Every Saturday afternoon, around four PM, Albert left his house and went
out to dinner with his social club at Beaumont House, the two Michelin
star restaurant on the river. Lucy had seen him leave every week at the
same time and Chris had mentioned Albert's predilection for scallops and
sweet wines. A couple of casual walk-pasts of the restaurant had
confirmed her suspicions. Knowing this, Lucy gathered a few useful
objects (mace, gloves, jacket, the lockpicking kit she'd bought a few
years back) while glancing out the window from time to time.
<br/><br/>
He left right on schedule. Lucy considered it a safe bet that he'd not
return any time soon; it was usually close to midnight when he got home.
She hadn't seen Chris return, considered it likely that he was still in
Albert's house.
<br/><br/>
Her first stop was Chris' door. She knocked sharply, listened for any
movement. After five seconds of perfect silence, she crouched down and
spied through the keyhole. It afforded her no new information. So, was
Chris in his flat, asleep? Was he mindlessly staring at the wall? Was he
at Albert's? No way to tell.
<br/><br/>
Nothing for it. Now or never.
<br/><br/>
Did she want to go down this road again? Was this the same mental
bullshit that had chased her down the rabbit hole before? Chris could
just be processing trauma, Albert could just be a great talker who
actually cared. That was possible, right?
<br/><br/>
After a moment's deliberation, she exited her building. She walked out
through the garden gate to the road, not wanting any neighbour to spot
her walking between her home and Albert's. She walked around the
perimeter of the estate and advanced back up that same path she'd trod
the first time she saw her new home. She'd avoided that path as much as
possible since, didn't want to see those clay heads with their too-real
expressions and wanton disregard for good taste.
<br/><br/>
The gate shuddered open, seemingly hesitant to allow her passage. She
strode through hoping to look more determined than she felt. Gravel and
stone crunched and clicked as she made her way towards the house,
furtively glancing left and right.
<br/><br/>
Lucy stopped when she reached the part of the path where the heads
started.
<br/><br/>
They'd all been turned, all faced towards her. Fifty forlorn faces, grey
and motionless, gazing at her hopelessly.
<br/><br/>
Impossible ideas tugged at the neglected corners of her consciousness.
Had they turned of their own volition, knowing nobody was supposed to be
approaching? They do say that gargoyles and grotesques are supposed to
serve as guardians, no? Were these baked earth faces somehow aware of
her? Did they mean her harm?
<br/><br/>
Lunacy, of course. She knew that. Nonetheless she was tense as she made
her way past the heads, benefactors of Albert's proprietary
weather-proofing process.
<br/><br/>
She followed the wall around to a rear door, peeked in the window. The
kitchen. Quick look about, no company, no direct line of sight to any
windows. Perfect. She crouched down, pulled her roll of picks from the
inside pocket of her oversized leather jacket. She was a little rusty
but managed to pry open the door within a couple of minutes.
<br/><br/>
Inside, she closed the door behind her gently and immediately registered
a low, vibrating hum. She held her breath for a moment, ears pricked up
in search of the sound's source, and of any indication of Chris within
the landlord's house. After several long seconds, she was satisfied that
the hum was a product of some old machinery somewhere. It was an old
house, it could be some monstrous boiler far past its proper lifespan.
Perhaps something to do with Howard's sculpting. A furnace idling in the
workshop. She filled her lungs, nose wrinkling with the scent of far too
much air freshener.
<br/><br/>
Quick, light footsteps towards the front of the house. She passed the
doors which led to the living room and Albert's workshop -- she noted
the humming was louder there -- before stopping outside the study. If
there were answers to be found, that seemed like a good place to start.
<br/><br/>
She placed an ear against the door, counted to three. Nothing. At least,
nothing she could hear over whatever baroque machinery had been left
running. It was uncomfortably warm in the hallway; fine rivulets of
sweat formed on her brow. Her hand went to the door knob, eased it
counter-clockwise, and pushed it open. The slightest creak raised her
heart rate.
<br/><br/>
She slid into the study.
<br/><br/>
And was immediately grabbed and pushed sideways into a bookcase.
<br/><br/>
Chris had his hands around her throat, looking at nothing with vacant
eyes and an idiot grin.
<br/><br/>
Lucy's vision distorted almost immediately, the pressure on her carotid
artery sending sparks to her eyes and a thrumming whistle to her ears.
She moved her hands to his, tried to get her fingers between him and her
neck. No chance. He was not a large man, barely average in height, but
had the bear-like mitts of a seasoned labourer.
<br/><br/>
Mace.
<br/><br/>
Her hand went to her pocket, retrieved the small spray can. She mouthed,
'Sorry,' and unloaded the noxious pepper spray into her neighbours eyes.
<br/><br/>
He did not appear to notice. Didn't even blink.
<br/><br/>
Enough splashed back on Lucy to affect her, though.
<br/><br/>
Bile rose in her throat as liquid pain scraped and crawled through her
corneas, beat against the lenses of her eyes. The world grew dim and she
felt as though she were suddenly aware of the rotation of the Earth.
<br/><br/>
She dropped the mace can, clawed at Chris' face. Her right hand reached
to the bookshelf beside her, grabbed an ornament. She introduced it to
the side of Chris' head.
<br/><br/>
His grip slackened before falling away.
<br/><br/>
He crumpled to the ground, unmoving.
<br/><br/>
Lucy slid down the wall, gulping down mouthfuls of air that tasted like
blood and blinking away tears. She gingerly touched her neck, felt the
tenderness of her punished flesh.
<br/><br/>
When the room had righted itself and learned to stay still, Lucy rose
and cautiously stepped over to Chris' unmoving form.
<br/><br/>
Her eyes grew wide, her throat expelled a timid squeak.
<br/><br/>
She realised she was still holding the ornament used to dent Chris'
skull. She examined it momentarily. A little figurine in the style of a
grotesque, a bat-winged little distorted figure with animalistic
features and a weatherproof scowl.
<br/><br/>
Slowly her eyes drifted back to Chris.
<br/><br/>
To his dented, but not bleeding, head.
<br/><br/>
Where the skin had broken, it revealed greyish solid matter beneath.
Entirely unlike bone, it was more akin to the heads that lined Albert's
garden path.
<br/><br/>
She crouched, felt his neck for a pulse, felt nothing. Her cheeks grew
moist, but she stayed silent.
<br/><br/>
Chris' scarf had fallen loose when he hit the floor. Lucy's eyes were
drawn to a faint red line on his neck. She crouched down, removed the
scarf entirely. Her brow furrowed in confusion, jaw tightened with
barely suppressed horror. The red line was some sort of recent scar, no
doubt. She moved around her fallen friend, examined him from every
angle. The scar unquestionably circumnavigated his neck.
<br/><br/>
She stood, leant on the nearest wall and took several deep breaths.
Nothing made sense. Her eyes darted about the room, caught on the spine
of a particular book resting on Albert's desk. Something about it was
off, irregular. It had a sort of magnetism, or gravity. A compelling
force that drew her to it. Lucy stepped over Chris and approached the
desk, examined the book. The finish looked less professional than most
of the volumes in the library, possibly even hand-bound. The cover was a
sort of soft leather, no text on the spine to indicate what it
contained. Only a small spiral design. Her hand, almost of its own
accord, began to drift towards it.
<br/><br/>
The odd little book felt so strange in her hands, the coolness of the
thing penetrated through her gloves in barely a moment. She flicked
through a few pages. Obscure diagrams, anatomical studies of the human
head, what could be chemical formulae, every item of notation and every
word in a strange alphabet she'd never seen before. Utterly
undecipherable.
<br/><br/>
She grunted and snapped the book closed. She couldn't read it, but she'd
take it with her. She had to. It slid easily into one of her jacket's
voluminous side pockets.
<br/><br/>
She raised her left hand to her temple and rubbed in small circles. Her
heart threatened to burst out of her chest. Things had gone so damn
sideways, what was she supposed to do?
<br/><br/>
The only thing that seemed viable, sensible, was to continue searching,
to find out what Albert was doing to people. Chris couldn't be the only
one. But where next?
<br/><br/>
She paced in tiny circles, still rubbing her temple. Scattered thoughts
bounced off the walls of her skull and defied her attempts to rally
them. Her breath grew shallow and rapid. Sparks darted across her field
of vision. And she couldn't, not even for a moment, get the damn
thrumming out of her head. Mechanical noise picking at the frayed edges
of her composure. She hated it, Wanted to break whatever made it. Where?
*Where?!*
<br/><br/>
Her hands fell to her sides. She stopped, turned to face the door.
<br/><br/>
The workshop.
<br/><br/>
Once more she stepped over Chris. She left the study, closed the door
behind her, paced over to the workshop entrance. She had abandoned
caution by this point; anyone that hadn't heard her altercation with
Chris wasn't going to hear her stomping around and opening doors.
<br/><br/>
She let herself into the room. The hum became a cacophony and the
workshop stank of earth and turpentine. In the centre, two plastic
looking sofas faced each other with a small, cheap coffee table between.
The outside edges of the room were dominated by work surfaces containing
all manner of wicked looking tools; chisels and knives, hammers and
scalpels. Nothing out of the ordinary for a sculptor.
<br/><br/>
At the far end of the room was a small set of steps leading to a door, a
basement of some sort. The worst of the smell seemed to come from there.
That would likely be where the clay was kept and prepared.
<br/><br/>
The steps were slick, thin and treacherous. The door at the bottom was
locked, but only with a cheap padlock. Lucy quickly removed it with her
picks. More steps on the other side took her much deeper than she'd
expected the basement to go; the ceiling was high and there could easily
have been four feet of solid matter between that and the floor above.
<br/><br/>
The chamber was full of bulk bags of clay, shelves full of myriad vials
and flasks, stained books, obscure machinery. One huge and active
machine in particular noisily dominated the centre of the room, larger
even than the currently operating -- and blisteringly hot, even from the
stairway -- industrial oven at the far end. A huge brass and steel
frame, a lidded wooden box at the centre of it. Several glass flasks of
various fluids were suspended above a system of tubes, the whole thing a
circuit driven by what seemed to be steam pistons. The pressure no doubt
came from the oven, the heat from which probably produced the bubbling
in the largest of the three vials, filled with a milky liquid. The two
other flasks contained some thick brown substance, a consistency like
honey by the look of it. Down here a range of scents were on offer,
turpentine grappling with aniseed and mouldy earth for dominance.
<br/><br/>
Lucy advanced towards the lidded box at the centre of the contraption,
hand outreached for the handle at the front. Her fingers wrapped around
warm brass, lifted up the front of the box.
<br/><br/>
Inside, twitching, was Chris' head. Eyes and mouth sewn shut, rough
muslin around the base of the neck with tubes protruding out. The device
was pumping those strange liquids through the blood vessels of his
dismembered head, somehow keeping him alive, judging by the sweat and
the constantly shifting facial expressions.
<br/><br/>
Lucy screamed and backed away, kept stepping until her back met the
wall.
<br/><br/>
Then the door slammed.
<br/><br/>
She turned to face the stairs, her scream dying in her throat.
<br/><br/>
Albert stood at the entrance to the room, hammer and chisel in his left
and right hands respectively, with the lumbering form of Chris behind
him. Chris' head -- at least, the head currently residing atop his
shoulders -- was still dented, now shedding grey dust. One of his eyes
madly swivelled in the socket, the other stared blankly ahead. He still
wore that dumb grin.
<br/><br/>
'Your head's not right, young lady,' Albert said, 'But don't worry. I
can fix that.'
<br/><br/>
    THE END]]>
</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, November 2 2024</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
